Now let's go out our panel component which will include information about the channel that users currently
on.
I had to the Minute panel file then are met a Panel folder import some components from semantic UI grab
segment accordion header and icon who use an accordion component here will be within a segment component
and first will have our header.
It'll be at age 3.
We attached to the top of the segment and we'll have the text about hashmarks and the channel name which
will display dynamically in a bit then we'll have our accordion component will be styled with a style
prop and attached as well by setting the attached prop to true.
And within our accordion component we have a number of segments each of which will be conditionally
shown when we click on the title.
So when you click on this first accordion title if the active index is zero and that's the index we're
going to give this part of the accordion if active index is zero it'll be active it will display the
content associated with the title that we're creating.
So add an active index property to state said initially 0 will restructure it within Rander.
So each of these tidal areas as well as their related content will have a given index and we'll add
an unclick to each of them if we click on a title we're going to set the active index and therefore
display the part of the accordion with an index of a certain value.
So two active index we're passing event and title prop's which will give us access to the index that
we set on the title.
So if we click on a certain part of the accordion we'll grab the index from the title props are passing
is that active index and also grab active index from St..
We're going to update active index with a variable called new index if active index is equal to the
index on our total props.
We get the value of negative 1 otherwise the index that's being passed when we click a given part of
the accordion and which will set new index to the active index it will update it and show that part
of the according with the given index value that we're setting in St. and within the title we're going
to put an icon first with the name of dropdown will be present within every accordion title that we
have in our accordion.
And then we'll add our own custom icon with the name of info here on this part of the accordion.
We're going to have channel details that we set for each channel
and then as I mentioned we'll have the content related to a given title to display those according to
the active index value will need to ground the active Prah that we supplied to the accordion title for
active index is being compared with zero.
And for now we'll just give our content the text of details we'll copy both the title and content and
paste another segment to the accordion underneath where will then change the index to one and compare
active index to one here.
Change the icon to user circle.
And our second icon this will be the area for our top posters and here with the accordion content we'll
compare active index with one again and then in the next segment that we'll paste and we'll compare
active index with to have an index of two Nikon a pencil.
Alternate the text will be created by within the title
compare active in text to within the accordion content.
The active prop and we'll just give it the full text of Creator for now.
So now we have our accordion we can toggle between different segments of it and we can see the default
text that we put in each area.
But now we want to hide the metal panel whenever we click on a direct messages channel.
We only want to see the metal panel to give us the user information whenever we click on a new public
channel.
So we're going after Jesus.
We're going to pass down and is private channel.
The value is private channel to our metal panel as we know we need to give it a key so that it renders
properly we give it a key with the current channel ID by first making sure we have a current channel
value and will receive that
in our state panel panel set the state property to private channel
and within render if we're currently in a private channel
and we can also restructure that from state if we're on a private channel.
We want to return not we want to return nothing.
We'll save that
and I'll try navigating to a direct messages channel and you can see that the Metapad goes away but
appears once again whenever we go back to a public channel.