Now we want to display channel information in each of the accordion segments that we created.
And we want to do that as we change the channel so we want to provide dynamically to them at a panel.
Information about the current channel so passed down current channel information as prox dramatic channel
component and more set that in state as the property name channel will do structure that our state object
and first within the header will grab channel don't name the channel name and we can channel details
where the accordion content we will just output channel about details.
The posters will cover that in the later section for our top posters and then in the last accordion
segment where we want to display who created a given channel will first use an image component which
will grab from semantic UI and we're going to set the source of that to channel that created by.
Avatar can get the user's avatar created the channel and then underneath that or add the name channel
that created by that name will save both of those files.
And when we head back to our app we don't get anything because we're getting this error can't read property
name of no.
So it takes a certain amount of time for in our global state the channel data to be said.
So we want to set up a conditional where if we don't have a channel we're going to return NULL just
like we did with private channel.
So then as the channel data is put on global state we get information about it.
We get our channel details and we get are created by user and their avatar and name now another way
of handling this.
Waiting for a channel to come in is will remove the conditional and instead of returning all will a
loading prop to our segment.
So if we don't have any channel data we'll say not channel will provide a loading spinner to the entire
segment and then for each data each piece of data that we're getting will set up a conditional rule.
First make sure that we have channel data with say channel and then use the double and operator to display
the property on the channel.
We'll do that for each of those dynamic values that we added.
So now we can see this loading spinner.
And as our channel data comes in
will refresh the page one more time so you can see that we're getting a floating splinter over the entire
metal panel.
And then as a last step or add a component to the last segment and put in the username and image into
that does the format be created by information a bit better.
I'll set this as an H3 set an image prop of circular on the image component.
So now if we take a look at our created by segment we can see that the user name is a bit bigger and
the Avatar where the creator is now circular.