Now part of the last step we want to display all the top posters for a given channel all of the individuals
who posted the most in a given channel.
So back in our messages component we're going to head up to the ad message listener function and execute
a new function that will create called Count user posts.
And I'll take all the loaded messages
we can ABA's new function anywhere but all down to count unique users and add count user posts underneath.
So can't use a purse.
We'll take the accumulated array of messages.
Priest channel will create a variable called user post which will store the return value of iterating
over this messages or a with the reduce method and the accumulator for Reduce will be initially set
to an empty object not an empty array.
Will loop over every message.
We'll first check to see then the body of produce whether there is a property on the accumulated object
with the name of the current message username.
If so we're going to take the object that this using named property is set equal to and increment its
Count property by 1.
Otherwise we're going to add a new object onto the accumulated object the property name of the username
who created the message.
And this will have a property of Avatar the user's avatar as well as a count of 1.
Since this is the first time finding a message with the given username and then at the end will return
the accumulator and then we want to log the object that stored within user posts.
So if we take a look at our console after the page loads we can see the change that we're currently
on.
We get an object with a number of properties each set equal to a username with an avatar value and a
count value set equal to the count of messages they've added to a given channel.
So this is what all use within the metal panel to display the top posters but instead of just logging
this object we want to put it on global state so the Metapad can make can make use of it so won't create
a new action which will execute called set user post.
It will take that user post object will create the type for it within the types file called set user
posts that will be equal to a string in the same name.
And now to create a function in the index file of our actions folder.
Once again this will be called to user post.
It will take some user post data and it's going to return an object first with the type from action
types that say user posts and then the payload and it'll have just the property name of user posts with
the value of user posts then within our reducers folder we're going to add another property to initial
channel state.
User posts set equal to no initially will add a new case to a channel reducer of action types that set
user posts where will return an object.
Are we spread all of the initial values of state and update only the user posts property to action not
Pallo the user posts.
So now we can make use of this new action on our products object.
But to put it there for our messages component we need to grab the connect function from reactors X
and or import our action site user post
you know down to the bottom to execute our connect function
to make our new action available within the messages component.
So malmsey to prop's will be said to know and will plucker site user post from app dispatched approx.
We'll save all of our files.
And back to our app if we take a look at our redux tools
we take a look at our channel property of say we should see an updated user posts property containing
all the values that we had before logged to our consul.
Now that we're putting our user posts object on global state going to head to after J us and use maps
to props to get the current value of user post from state that channel that user posts and pass it down
once again by structuring user posts from the app prop's down to the metal panel component.
So now head to our panel and we'll
receivers directly from prop's instead of putting it on state
or pluck user posts off from the prop's object then we head down to recording content per our top posters
area or first check to make sure that we have a value for user posts.
And if so it will execute a function called display top posters which will pass the user posts object
to will create this new function above or render
so display top posters will take the posts and to make this object easier to work with will use the
function object that entries so except our post object that we're passing to it.
And just to display how object or entries works.
Well create a simple object stored by the variable a couple of properties object that entries does is
it will take this object and convert both the key for an object as always its value to its own array
and put that within an array.
So in the end when we pass an object to object all the entries will have an array of arrays.
So we can use any array method we like with the first array method that we can make use of is sort so
sort takes a function with premolars and B.
And if we take B of the index of 1 minus a or the index of 1 we can compare the count value of each
of the top posters and show them in descending order from Greatest count of post to kind of post.
Then we can use the map method and within the parameters of map we can restructure the key and value
for each of the elements of the array
and then use them in the markup that will output in order to display all of our top posters.
So the component that we need is the list component from semantic UI
and will actually wrap our conditional are we have user posts and our display top posters function in
a list component
and then back within display top posters will iterate over the list item.
So the key props for the list item will be set to the index of the current element for iterating over
so we can also grab the index even though where destruction can value when the parameters of MT and
within the list item will add an image component.
The prop of Avatar and a source of Baldauf Avatar
will have a list content component within that would be a list Hetter will make that as an ATAC the
content of key.
So the key will be the name of the top poster and then a list description with value Valder account
and the text of posts to get the total count of posts that they've added to a given channel.
If we take a look at that you can see a given user their name their avatar and the number of posts they've
contributed.
We switch to a different channel.
We can see we just have one poster here since there is only one user who's added post to this re-act
channel.
And then finally at the end if we want to limit the number of top posters to a specific amount we can
use the slice method and say get only the first five top poster say if we have more than five elements
within our array.
And lastly if we want to handle the case that we're incorrectly formatting this post value if sometimes
we need to provide the text of post.
If the number of posts is singular or plural if there's multiple posts or zero we can create this format
count function which takes the Valder count amount and we'll first check to see if the number that it
takes is greater than 1 or equal to zero.
If so you want to use post plural.
Otherwise post singular for the text.
Now if we take a look at top posters and see that we have multiple for a given user it's plural and
if we just have one post it's singular.