Let's go over the tools that you'll need to have on your computer to complete this project first you'll
need to have installed.
No genius you can get that at no jast dot org.
And there you'll find options to download the stable version of note which is currently eight point
twelve.
For the most recent version ten point ten.
I'd recommend going with the stable version and it's the version that Noad recommends as well.
We're using firebase for a back and for our database for our storage in this application.
So you need to create an account with firebase that based on Google dot com and you can either do that
now or you can do it in the relevant section where we set up our base.
It's up to you and the code editor abusing which is optional of course is Visual Studio code and you
can grab it for free at Kodak Visual Studio dot com.
There you'll find options for Mac Windows or Linux computers.