Throughout the course of creating our app we're going to be working with a couple of browser extensions
that will make doing things like debugging and looking at state and prop's a lot easier.
And these are the reactionary duck step tools that are available to anyone using either chrome or Firefox
browsers.
And right now I'm going to show you how to install both of these extensions if you're using Chrome and
this will work for Chrome Canary as well.
If you're using the developer version of chrome like I am.
So first when you have chrome open you had two of the top windows panel and head down to the extensions
option which will take you to the extensions page at Chrome forks Asheboro slash extensions.
You'll see all the extensions that you currently have installed.
And just to know you can remove these in the future.
So if you ever want to remove what we're installing right now just click on the Remove button back in
this page or click on the hamburger icon in the top left hand corner and in the side panel that opens
the very bottom you will click on Open Chrome Web store.
So here in the top left hand corner you want to search for first re-act tools or re-act developer tools.
And the first option that comes up should be the one that we want will then click on Abda chrome confirm
that we want to add the extension.
Click on Add extension.
We should see this confirmation window pop up that it's been added to Chrome
and now we need to do is search for Reducto tools and do the same again it should be the first option
that pops up quick on an extension
and then a second hopefully that should be added as well.
And all you'll need to do in the future to open these developer tools when we have our Riak development
server up and running is right click it inspect to open our console then click on the forward arrow.
Well see here when we're actually working with the re-act app a re-act option to open the dev tools
and the same will apply to redux.