Now take a look at Starring public channels that we like and putting them within a star component just
above our channels component will first create this start component within our side panel.
Go to side panel file and write it on an ether user panel will create a custom stored component will
create a file for it on our side panel folder
where we will import re-act up at the top.
This will be a staple component.
The class name of starred
I have our render and return and we'll export it
back inside panel.
Make sure to import that
then for the markup with an our started component.
You can just go to channels and grab entire menu menu component so that will have a structure very similar
to our channels
no need to import all of the components that we're using from semantic UI on the menu and Icom will
change the icon name to star and give it a text a start or remove the icon and we'll display the number
of star channels the start started channels property more past our channels down to the splayed channels
function.
So create started channels within our state object that bit equal to an empty array the structure from
state within render.
Now we need to grab the display channels function since we're calling it.
So we'll grab all that from channels.
We'll change the argument there to start channels and paste it in everywhere wherever using channels
parameter or remove the label for notifications.
We'll add to state the active channel property equal to an empty string and also need set active channel
in order to update that value.
And grabbed the entire change channel function
in order to execute it.
And from that we can remove clear notifications as well as where we're setting the channel property
in state since we don't have that here.
And or import connect from Raftery Ducs
as well said current channel and set private channel
to allow us to switch to other public channels and update those values in our global state and connect
at the bottom or up start with it.
So that maps state to props now and the structure both said current channel and said private channel
from map dispatched to props.
Now when we have new channels added to our start component we'll be able to display them to change channels
just like we can on our channels component.
So an active class reach channel that we're on and display the number of channels within start.