Now we want to set up an on click handler to the star icon within our messages Hetter we'll head to
the messages had her component button on clicked the icon will set it equal to handle star which will
handle starring a given channel and will create the function for this within in our messages component.
First to add a property to a state called Channel Sard said initially the false so this will keep track
as to whether a given channel has been started previously.
So now create our Hindu star function when we call Hindol star.
We want to change is channel started to its opposite value and will do so using an inline function of
a concert stage or get access to the entire previous state.
No update is channel started according to that.
Who said it to not.
Previous state DOT is channel starved though always give us the opposite value.
And then within the callback to says state when is channel start is updated.
Will execute a function called Star Channel.
This will check to see first of all if is channel start is set to true.
If so for now we'll just log the Texstar.
Otherwise if it's at the Falls we'll log On-Star to add the functionality for storing and unstring a
channel there in just a minute then down with a render function we want to do structure is channel start
from state and to our messages.
We want to pass handle star handle star function via props as well as is channel starved.
So now we're making an All-Star available to the messages header for our icon.
Now execute the handle star function
and now on the icon we want to change the appearance of it.
When a given channel has been started so based on whether its channel started to set to true either
give the name of the icon star or star outline and asked for the color or set up a similar turn every
where if a channel star who set the color to yellow or black.
If not we'll save that now.
Test this out within our.
We'll try clicking on the icon for a given public channel and we should see that the icon turns yellow.
We see the log of star if we click on it again we see On-Star and changes back to black and outlined
and we can click on this as many times as we like and our is Channel star property is always updated
correctly back within messages.
Let's add the functionality within Star Channel to actually update the data within our database.
And in particular we want to update the user object for a given user we want to add a stored property
to the use of that stars the channel and the stored property start.
Object will include an array of IDs for each channel start that ID will include information about that
channel the name of the channel the details about it as well as who created the channel with a created
by object.
And that will include the name of the user as well as their avatar
if we add this
can see an example of what this will look like.
This started property with an array of IDs for each channel that starred.
So to implement this all out we had back to start channel and we want to grab the users raw since we're
updating a given user and their data.
So create users or property and state that to firebase that database start for the string of users
and we want to select a given child of that ref based on the user's ID.
So add some template literals one interpolate the user's ID from state and and slash start to add this
new property.
Then we want to use the update method where on the object want to dynamically change the idea of the
channel and its related data.
So the idea will be set to an object with a name property a details property set to the channel name
and the channel details and state will have are created by object
and we'll get that from the does data channel that created by that name and their avatar we just change
the end of that path.
We created by Avatar.
So for every channel that we store we're adding a new channel ID with all the information about it.
Then in the case we want to take the same child the same user id slash start
and then the child of that would be the channel ID and use the Remove method or once again we can catch
any errors by making sure the error is not equal to no.
And if so we use a console error to display it in our console.
So save that now to test this out.
Let's star our first channel once we do that.
You can see the new START property added to our current user which contains the channel ID of the channel
we start as well as all of its related information within it we can add to the second channel star that
as well.
But when we flip back to the first channel we dont see the star as yellow anymore.
Yet we still have all of the information for that channel within our starred property in the database.
So are you I doesn't reflect what we have in our database and even if we refresh the star is still black
and outlined.
Do you get information about the channels that a given user has previously stored or create another
listener which will execute within component amount.
So when the component mounts we're going to call add user stars listner which will take the current
channel ID as was the current user ID
and the add user stars Lisner will take both of these values in order to get all of the channels and
the related information about the channels that the user has stored will take the users or select a
child based on the user id and a child start to get the entire Sard property want to use the once method
to get its value.
And then within the then statement we'll get the data and we'll make sure that data value is not equal
to know.
So we have a value for stored property and will create a variable called Channel IDS will get all the
channel IDs that a given user has saved and get an array of them using object keys and will take this
array of IDs and use the includes method and check to see if our given channel ID is present within
it will set the return value to previously stored.
And if it finds that within this array it includes finds it to return a value of true.
And we want to update is channel start based on the previously stored variable but stored in that will
save that back and we can see immediately that our star for our first channel is yellow reflecting what
we have in our database and a star for our second channel is yellow as well so we can toggle that reverse
of the page.
You can see our first panel once again is stored in the second channel is not.
Which lines up with our database for our given user.