Now that we're able to star in On-Star channels we want those channels to show up and our users start
component.
So had a side panel and in order to display all the channels that are user start we need to have information
about the current user so passed down the current user prompt to start
and then within start
like we have another components will create a user property referencing our current user that we're
passing down and only the user's ref to reach out to our users collection.
So import firebase from a couple of folders up
and the users ref will take the database module and the user's ref.
So when the component mounts we want to set up a listener
so execute a function called out listeners that will create
an add listeners will listen on the users off for any new changes to the starred property.
So first we need to select a child on it according to the users you ID with in component amount we can
set up a conditional to make sure that first we have a value in state for our current user and once
we do we can pass down their ID and will receive that and our listeners function as User ID.
So now we can select the child with the user ID and their start property.
And first we want to listen for when a user stars a new channel.
So listen for the child after the event and then the snap callback will create a variable called Star
Channel where I will assemble an object new object with an id property set to snapshot key and then
spread the rest of the values with the spread operator will spread all of its value to get the rest
of the properties for a given channels information and then we're going to set the state we're going
to update the start channels array by creating a new array where we take all the previous values of
started channels and once again spread them in to the array with the spread operator and add this new
start channel object.
At the very end and we also want to listen for when a channel is unstored will take the users off again.
And select user ID as a child and start as a child and listen for the child removed event.
So here we want to remove some channel information that was previously in our star channels array.
So once again will create an object not assigned to a variable called Channel to remove.
Once again you have the idea of now Otaki will spread the rest of the values for that channel into the
new object or create a variable called Filter channels and are going to take the star channels or use
the filter method on it to make sure this new array doesnt have an element that has an ID property equal
to the ID of the channel to remove object.
And finally we want to update the Sard channels array and state the filtered channels array that we
just created.
Now save all of our files back to our app and now you can see in our start area we have both of the
channels that weve stored we act in javascript so we can click on them and navigate to the channel and
also On-Star them and as we On-Star them you'll see that they are immediately removed.
From the start component we can add them back by favoring them once again.