Let's build up the basic structure for our component go to after jazz and remove the art class as well
as the component import from react or change to a stateless functional component.
And it will have one component from semantic you I react.
The great component include a set of grid tags and within the grid will have a number of custom components
will have a color panel component side panel component messages component and finally a metal panel
component.
Will create a folder or a color panel
which will include a color panel component the top will import reacts.
This will be a stateful component so it will be class color panel sends re-act up component will have
our render and return.
Now we'll just return to Divx.
The text of color panel and then export it
can copy all of this markup
and we'll create our next folder within the components folder side panel with its corresponding component
side panel and paste all that in all the markup be copied.
Change the class the side panel the text the side panel and the export side panel
will do the same for our messages component will include file of messages pasted in our markup
and change the class name.
The text in the export will have one final folder metal panel
with a component of the same name placed in the markup
so the class met a panel.
The text that met a panel and export the component within Apple import.
Each of these components then their respective folders color panel from color panel side panel from
side panel slash side panel
messages from messages slash messages
a panel from a panel slash panel and save all those files.
Take a look at our app component.
You can see the components are lined up next to one another.
Now we'll use grid to organize the components a bit better.
Set the comms to equal class the movie app and I'll give it a style prop with the background rule set
to the Texaco Tripoli
now will leave the color panel inside panel off to the side.
They won't have their own call or wrap messages and met a panel in a set of grid column tags
for messages we want to offset it from color panel inside panel by giving it a style Propp
and that will include a rule where a margin lapped reset to 320 pixels.
I will do the same with a metal panel
wrap it in Grid column tags will give it a width of four.
Now since semantic UI uses a 16 point grid system this means that the metal panel column will take up
with the fourth of the page with we save that file.
Take a look at our out you can see the basic structure that each of our components within our chat will
have.