With an IRA component we'll begin with our side panel.
The first thing I'll add to it is a user panel or will be able to log out of the app withinside panel
or place the starting div with a menu component from semantic you react
and the menu will contain a number of custom components but first will add a number of props to it give
it a size of large gimpy inverted prop to make the text that will have within the menu light and color
and make it fixed to the left hand side of our app component.
It will be a vertical menu.
Will give it a style prompt where the background will be set to the tax code.
4c receive 4C and will give it a slightly larger than usual font size of 1.2 REM's
we save that.
Take a look at our menu here.
On the left hand side of the app as I mentioned we're going to add some custom components within it.
Then the menu tags first will be the user panel.
So we'll create the user panel component within our side panel folder
import re-act which will be a class based component a stateful component of our render and all return.
We all start out with a component of grid from semantic.
I react
on it will set the style tag make its background the same Next go horse E-3 see 4C within our group
tags will have a column
row have a grid row.
We can have a number of rows within each column and on it will set the style.
In particular it's padding to 1.2 m's in a margin of zero
within the row tags
include a header make sure to import that from semantic.
I react
I'll just add a comment bubblehead are saying this is our main application.
It in the head or we can have this set of content tags to specify the text content we'll make this dev
chat will give our header an inverted prop will float to the left and we'll make it an H to within our
head it will include an icon so import that will have the name code.
We save that mixture to export it at the bottom.
Export user panel
and then import it within side panel.
We save once again and see our dev chat had her up at the top with our code icon.
But on top of having a header within our great call column underneath the row we'll have a user dropdown
or a user can select a number of options.
And now we want to include the option of being able to log out of our app
and look for the closing tag for a grid call or add another header the style and it's paddings that
to point to five AMS and this will be as an H for an inverted once again.
And we'll put the dropdown component within the header will bring in dropdown component
will set the trigger for the dropdown.
What will trigger opening the options within the dropdown and an options Propp which will show will
display all the available options for our user.
The trigger will be a spam with the text of user.
The options will be a function which will execute as dropdown options.
So create dropdown options as a function on our user panel and will immediately return from that an
array and this array will have a number of objects within it would be a text property on each object.
For the first one we'll just have a span where it tells us that we're signed in as a certain user
and this first option will be disabled since it won't be something that we can click on.
We're just telling our user that they're currently signed in the next object will have text property
with this band set to change avatar.
Now a user will be able to click on this soon enough to be able to change their avatar.
And then we'll have an option for a user to sign out.
We need to provide key properties to each of these objects so I'll just give them different names.
Sample the first object will have a key of user.
Next will have a key of Avatar and The Last Word a key of Sino will save that
you can take a look at our dropdown and click on it.
You can see our options for change Avatar and sign up.