The last section we created our user panel component which includes a dropdown or we have this sign
out option.
Now we want to add the functionality to that so when we click on it or redirect it to the log in page
and our user is signed out so within the option for sign out within our dropdown point add an on click
to the span and reference a function called handle sign out and the sign out or user are going to need
firebase or import firebase up at the top.
And it should be from two folders up.
We use the art module again and we use a method on it called Sign out.
So execute that and we can add on and then statement where once we once we sign out using firebase we
can log the text find out if we save that
and open our log.
We select sign out when we're authenticated we see are signed out log in the console.
Now if we try redirecting we're going manually to log in or out.
We're just going to see this loading spinner.
Now that's because we didn't set up a case within our state changed function within index us for when
our user is not found by the listener.
So in this health statement we want to push to the log in route and we want to create a new action which
will clear our user from the global stage to do that will create a new action go to types first.
We know we need to create a type for each action will create a type for clear user set to the steering
clear user create a function of the same name within the index file over our actions folder.
And a clear user won't take any arguments all it will do is it'll just return an object with the type
of action types dot clear user referencing are clear clear user type then we'll head to our reducers
go to our user reducer.
We'll set up a new case for action types that clear a user or we want to return
the initial user state where our current user is set to know to do that to spread all of the properties
from our initial users to.
We can just write this spread operator dot dot dot initial user state and set loading to false.
So we're seeing loadings Vinter because we're not setting the loading to false.
So now that we're calling clear user we can execute it on our prop's object if we bring it in for our
actions folder and reference it within map dispatch to prop's within our K'NEX if we save that we head
back to her app and refresh.
We should now be able to see our log in page if we take a look at our redux step tools and see that
our clear user action was executed where it just set loading to false and current user is no.
If we log in again
it submit or set user action sets or user data in state we can log out or sign out a clicking on sign
out or redirected to log in our current user data set to know.
And if we try going to the component we're pushed back automatically to the log in page.