We want to display some user information within our dropdown in our user panel component in particular
the user name the user that's currently signed in and to do that.
One approach would be to bring in redux in particular to use the connect function we could grab connect
from re-act redux and at the bottom at our export can wrap the user panel component with it
and also maps to prop's by creating the maps to prop's function where we take taken the global state
and return an object with the properties that we want from it.
So for example we could grab the current user property when we set our user from the user property we
could create a prop on our crops object of current user the value state user to our current user and
optionally we could restructure the state the state parameter so that we could just change the path
to use our current user but we'll leave it at state.
And now that we're mapping this property to our prop's we could log it within render referencing it
with this property current user.
And when our component loads our user panel loads more refresh the page and see we have all of the user
data from our global state.
This is one approach to passing state down from our global state to an individual components such as
user panel
but to get the user name value within our dropdown we can create a state object where we have this user
property and instead of logging the value within render to update state object we can't do it from the
render function need to create a lifecycle method such as component and mount.
And then when we get that user data we can set the state and in particular this user property that we
created consented to the stop Propst that current user
and then using the user property and state we going to get the username and get that from this state
DOT user dot display name and save that if we reload.
You can see we're getting an error the areas we can't read the property display name of nolle.
So it looks like we're trying to get a property off of the user object before it is updated to change
that we can to set a conditional we're checking to see that we first have a value for our user property
or a user object and then include the display name property off of that.
So that works.
But this is a bit tedious to always set up a conditional for every value that we want off of the state
object or a property of the state object.
So another approach that we can take is to use a lifecycle method like component will receive props
or we've taken the props that we're getting
and set the state according to that we could set the user value to next Propst our current user.
So this will also work but to do this in every component in order to get the values from our global
state again requires a lot of code.
So we're going to take an alternate approach we're just going to directly set that user value and say
to this start Propst a current user and pass down the current user data a bit differently.
We're going to go to abduct Jap's
and this is where we're going to use the connect function to map state props to import connect from
reactor redux.
We're going to make sure that we're getting all of the values from states within one component or component
to add connect to the bottom of map state to prop's And here we'll just have one map state to prop's
function that will give us an object with all of the values that we need from our state.
And then just pass down the values that we need via props.
So first grab current user from state up user dot current user and we'll add current user as a property
first to our side panel which is where our user panel component lives will pass down.
Current User the proper current user and we'll restructure that props and our props object for at like
so past current user to current user problem we created for a side panel then with an assigned panel
we'll have his current user Propp within render we can pluck off that current user profit from this
stuff prop's
reference that is current user once again and pass that down to the user panel.
So now we're receiving the value for our current user directly within state via props and now.
But instead of setting up a conditional or using the connect function here you can just say this that
state that user data display name
can get the user name of our currently signed and user can change the trigger in our dropdown to this
state that user that display name as well.
Will save all those files.
If we head back to our out we can see immediately we have the name
of the user that's currently authenticated.
And both places in our dropdown
so passing the prop's pressing the global state down via props instead of using the connect function
only using the connect function in one place within our app component will provide a very convenient
way to pass state down to all of the components that will need to access information such as the user
data if we refresh again we can see that our user name is still there.