We're now passing our username to our user panel we also want to pass the avatar that we have in our
user data to it.
So within our trigger then the span will change.
The username path to user doesn't display name and with the structure there is a property from state
and within the span of this put this on multiple lines we'll put an image component right above the
name and the source for it.
Will be user dot photo Ural will give it a space property set to right in a proper avatar as well to
make it an avatar image will bring in the image component from semantic.
You react
we'll just bring it within our grid row or entire header.
We can save our file.
We take a look at our dropdown now you should see the avatar that we have for our currently authenticated
user.