Let's grab all the files that we need for our project to do so we'll go to the Euro get abduct com slash
read Barber slash re-act dash slack dash clone that contain all of the starting files that we'll need
for our act up as well as all the necessary dependencies for our project to grab these.
We'll click on the cloner download burn.
You can download all the files here as a zip file.
When set of that will be cloning them onto our computer.
Click on the clipboard icon and we'll go to our terminal or go to my code editor's since it has an integrated
terminal.
And if you're using VS code you can get control and then the till the button in order to open that can
also get a view of the top and then click on terminal and from here we want to select the folder where
we want our project to live in.
So all CD into that folder or CD onto my desktop and then we'll run get clone paste and the you are
all that we copied by clicking on the clipboard icon and then hit enter.
We take a look at that directory.
We should see the folder new folder that was added a reac slack clone or just drag that into my code
editor to load all the files within it.
And once you've done that we will then install all of the dependencies listed within the package that
Jason File by running NPM install.
Or you can just use the shortcut NPM I
upon running this will have a node modules folder that contains all of our dependencies and we'll be
able to start up and begin building our re-act application.