We've sold all the dependencies for a project now it can clear out the logging in our terminal and remove
any get files we might have brought down on me.
Clone this repo with our dash are Afkham get this or move any get files in our project.
We don't want to use someone else's version control.
But if you want to initialize.
You can just try to get a set up file tracking then all run NPM start to start up our development server
that should start up at localhost 3000 and show the home page the styles for page up create react at
so used create react to bootstrap of the starting project files and we'll go into the source folder
into APTA Jass and remove all the markup within the div tags or place that with the text of app or move
the class name of app and remove the logo import up at the top and delete the logo.
SVGA fall within the source folder as well.
You want to remove any initial style so go to after CSSA clear out all the style rules there.
We're going to create a new folder in the source folder for all of our components so this will be called
components.
While dragon ABTA Jason APTA CSSA into this newly created folder then since we change the path of app
going to within index that has changed Yep path to slash component's slash app save all of our files
and we should see on the home page just the text of app in the top left hand corner.
Now set up some routing per application.
Import a few things from the package re-act Rotterdam will first grab browser router and rename it as
a router as well as the switch and route components for our individual routes.
We'll house all of our routes within a stateless functional component called route
all of our individual routes will be within a switch component that's within the router component.
Our first round will be the route route.
We'll give it a path of just forward slash and connect it to the component at.
Now we want to render route instead of app since app is now a route.
We'll save that and we should still see the app text on our home page going to create a new folder within
our components folder called Auth. going to add the files and the components log in and register to
that folder.
And then register will import re-act up at the top.
This will be a staple component will say class register sends react a component will have its necessary
render function as well as the return.
For now we'll just return a div with the text of register and export at the bottom with export before
the register component grab all the markup that we just wrote and paste it within log in will change
the class the log in the text the log in and the export to the log and component then we'll create routes
for both of these new components within our index file.
Create a route with the path of log in that will reference the log in component and a path register
with the component of register and Obering and both of those components into index exit Jaspal import
log in from components off.
Log in can copy that and change the path to slash register at the end and the name to register.
And we want to add the exact keyword on the route path to make sure that we're not matching multiple
components which is what the switch component will do if we don't have that exact keyword there.
Then we can within our browser go to log in and the register routes.