Are going to be using firebase is the back end and databased our project.
Now firebase is a great choice for us since we're making a chat after we want users to be able to see
new messages in real time and firebase is what's known as a real time database it makes use of a technology
called web sockets in order to make data transfer very fast.
So we'll create an account with firebase of the fire based at Google dot com and we'll click on.
Once you've signed up go to a.
We've taken the con. The fire based at Google dot com.
We want to add a project by clicking on and project include our project name.
I'll give mine the name of re-act slack clone.
And you'll be asked to agree to their terms so quick the checkbox and click on Create project far based
on our create our project once our project is ready will click on the Continue button and will be taken
to a kind of admin panel for our project will begin by underneath the line get started by adding firebase
to your app will click on this code icon will give us some instructions and data will use to integrate
firebase with our web app underneath the Initialize firebase comment.
Want to grab both the Conficker object as well as the function call firebase start initialize app which
takes that config object or copy all that back to our app.
We're going to add a new file within our source folder for all of this and we copy it.
We're going to call this firebase dumb ass or pace that write in.
And since we're making use of firebase here and we're calling initialized app with all the configuration
data we're going to import firebase from firebase slash app
and we're going to import a few other packages as well.
Say So.
So dependencies I should say will import firebase slash off or authorization within our app
firebase slash database make use of the realtime database firebase flash storage Chole allow us to store
things like media files
at the very bottom we'll export firebase with export default.
To make that available to other parts of our app and if you'll notice the storage bucket property that
has an empty string we want to set up our firebase storage we'll go over to the storage tab in the left
hand side and in that page will click on get started or show some default security rules for our storage
to say.
Got it.
And from here we want to grab the URL up of the top after the G-S Ford slash forward slash that you
all that ends with Spot dot com.
Paste it directly into our storage bucket property to set up firebase storage.
Now I can save that file and start making use of firebase within our re-act.