One of the last steps that we need to take before deployment is that since we've set up a lot of listeners
within our components we need to win our component announce remove those listeners to begin the color
panel we'll set up a component will unmount lifecycle method and we'll call a function called remove
listener or remove the one listener that we have set up.
So reference users as well as the child that we're listening on of this starts data user ID and the
colors property.
And then finally call the off method in order to remove that listener that we set up with component
and mount So moving onto our message form component.
We have this upload task property and state which holds onto the currently uploading image.
And if our component mounts we don't want to remove a listener but we do want to cancel any uploads
that may be taking place.
So if upload task is not equal to know within state we're going to use the cancel method on it to cancel
uploading the file that might be within it and we'll set state to update the upload task properties
to know then we'll move on to the messages component and removing the listeners here or or quite a bit
more effort than the other components.
Again all set up component will unmount will execute this remove listeners function which will take
in a property from state of listeners set initially to an empty tray will collect the information about
each of the listeners that we set up on component mount with the listeners array and we'll add a new
element to the listeners are using this ad to listeners function that takes the id rather an event that
a given listeners using and within the function will first iterate over the listeners or to check to
see if we already have the data stored for a given listener by comparing the ID ref and event guys that
are passed in with each of the elements.
And if we can't find the index of an element with each of these values are going to add a new object
onto the Wisner's array creating a new listener object with the property name and values of ID ref an
event that are passed to it will set up a state where we'll update the listeners array by concatenating
this new listener object onto the listeners array.
Now go down to each listener and call add to listeners in order to collect the data for it to execute.
Add to listeners underneath where we're listening for the child added event for our typing wrap.
So passen to the function call Channel ID typing route and the channel additive and we can copy that
and go underneath the child removed for our typing graph and just change the event argument to child
or moved.
We'll then go to add message listener will change the wrap argument to ref and it will also pass in
the event of child added then create or remove listeners function which will do the work of removing
every listener whose data we have stored in this listener's array remove listeners will take the listeners
or they will use the for each method on it.
The listener will take the raw property on it.
Or put the listener ID value on as a child and then call off and pass listener event to the method.
Then within component of Mt..
If we have a channel and user we want to remove any listeners and we can structure the listeners array
there to pass to it.
And also within component will announce we want to grab the connected raw and call off on that as well.
Then moving on to our channels component we within the remove listeners function that we set up our
removing the channels ref listener.
But now we need to iterate over the channels or a state using for each in order to for each of the children
that we put on the messages or call off on them bypassing each channel ID as a child.
Then within direct messages
will set up component will on Mount
will execute remove listeners
and remove listeners would be rather simple in this case.
Well describe the users or call off on that
and grab the president's rah and call it as well as the connected ref will say that and close it.
Move on to a start.
Set up component will unmount their
We'll call a function remove listener.
Well we want to move one listener where we're listening on our users or off with the child
where we will interpolate the user id slash start and then call off on that.
And finally once we save all of our changes and removing all of our listeners
will once again use my deployed app.
Currently it looks like channels the start component as well as the color panel are being loaded successfully
along with the messages another user can still type.
We see that they're typing and when they add a new message we see it show up.