Going to take a look at securing our app by setting up some firebase rules.
But first we'll head into the user panel and we'll change the child for the storage ref and set the
path to Avatar slash users and sort of the dash that we previously had and the same for the message
form will change the path here within get path to chat slash private slash the interpolated channel
ID.
So this will make setting up some rules for a heart based stories a bit easier.
So to access our storage rules are going to go to the storage tab
and Normally we've been working in the files area but now we want to move to the rules area and this
is where we can set up some rules in order to better secure our store.
So we're not having any files added to our storage that we don't want.
So we're going to replace this bucket value with the name of our app.
In my case Riak slack clone and then end it with that app's Watcom or remove the code which starts with
match slash or pass and replace it with our own rule for the Avatar's path.
So this mash rule is going to match any new images that we're going to try to add to the Avatar's path
within our storage and we'll Mascha some path of slash users slash user ID and we wrap user ID and curly
braces since we're going to use this as a variable.
We're going to allow reads to images posted to our avatar path if requested off is not equal to know
if we have an authorized user and we're going to allow right to add a new image to our avatar path if
we have an authorized user if their ID is equal to the user id the end of the path that we're trying
to add an image to as well as if request resource content type if the content type of the image matches
the form.
Image slash dot star.
So if it's of any image type we're going to allow it to be posted to the Avatar path slash users slash
that user ID and we can also make sure that its size is less than 1 megabyte by saying request that
resource size less than 1 times a thousand twenty four times a thousand.
That equals 1 megabyte in terms of size and per images posted to our chat path will have a set path
which will match slash public and then end with the path of anything as represented with image path
equals star star.
Since we're using a random string in order to set the end of our image that we're adding to this path
we're going to allow reads once again if our users authenticated with requests that are not being equal
to know or copy all of the rules that we set for our write rules for our avatars no pasted in to write
rules here.
But we'll just remove where we're making sure that the users you idea is equal to the user ID.
Since we're not using that variable here then underneath are unmatching slash public.
We're going to match slash private and here our private channel once again consists of two user IDs
at the end.
User ID one and user ID to so there's as variables and then end with an image path sourced or are going
to allow reads if requests or doesn't know as well as if request or got new ID the ID of the user That's
requesting the image is equal to either user ID 1 or it's equal to user ID too.
So only the two users that we have for the given direct messages channel are going to be able to read
those direct messages no one else.
And we're going to allow right if our users authenticated and we can copy this conditional that we set
up for reading permissions.
And then we'll grab the remaining part of our first write rules or a set of write rules for avatars
where we're going to make sure that the resource has a content type of image slash whatever and that
the image size is less than 1 megabyte.
So all these rules
and the test is out back in our app we want to see if we can post messages with image content.
To each of our channels we'll first began with the public channel.
We can still upload an image there now and direct messages channel
will be the same.
We can also send an image message there and to change our avatar We'll select a different part of the
image that we previously used or crop it will click on change Avatar and now we can see within our avatar
preview that's been changed.
If we send a message our new avatar is included there as well.