This like we made our storage area more secure by setting the rules for what images could be added to
certain paths we're now going to add rules to our database to determine what data can be read or written
to for each of our collections.
So create a new rules Jason object first for our Channel's collection are going to allow reads with
this dot read Rule by making sure the user is authorized.
So if auth is not equal to no rechannel we have this dynamic channel ID.
Now you are going to allow rights we're going to allow users to create new channels and create this
channel ID value if authors on equal to no and we're going to validate each new channel that's added
with new data that has children we'll check to make sure each new channel added has the properties ID
name created by in details.
And we can additionally validate each of these properties within has children so validate the ID once
again using the validate rule.
We'll check to see if the value of this new data the value of the ID is equal to the channel ID will
make sure that the name on the channel has a length that is greater than zero and will copy this and
provide the same rule.
But for our details so the user thats adding the name and details for our new channel has to provide
some characters to them then for our messages collection.
It has a dynamic channel ID value will allow that to be read if authors are equal to know
will use validate again.
Where we want to take the child of the route.
In other words check to see if the channels collection plus this new channel ID exists within our database
using the exists method on each channel ID will have a unique ID preach message gets added or allow
a new message to be created and therefore write permission if authors non-equal to know.
And so this is for public channels and will validate what's attached to this message ID.
In other words all of the message information or any message that's added by checking to see if new
data has the children content user and time stamp it has those properties and doesn't have the property
image.
So this would be for a text message but we also want to handle the case that our message has image data.
So a copy of this conditional use and or operator and pasted in afterwards would replace the content
property with image and image with content.
So that would handle the case that we have an image message instead of a text message or validate the
content property.
If we have a text message
by making sure that new data value has a length greater than zero will do the same for image that it
has the length greater than zero and per user
we can validate them by making sure that they have the children ID name in Avatar.
So they at least have to have these three properties.
They don't have to have the stored or color properties.
Then we'll move on to our private messages collection where it will first have a unique ID that will
call you I.D. one and another one within it of you on YouTube or both of the user IDs or read only if
author is not equal to no and just like the role that we provided within our storage rules make sure
that you the one variable is equal to or that your ID or your ID to is equal to or that you ID
then that will contain a message ID reach message that's added to our private messages collection.
And we can just copy and paste all of the relevant validation that we added previously for a message
ID or messages collection.
Then we move on to President and here will read all our reads give our users authenticated and rights
if our users authenticated.
Of course we're just updating whether they're present within the app or not whether they're online and
will provide the same rules for typing.
So every user will enable reads and writes
and moving on to users will read if users authenticated
and it will have a unique ID value all our rights.
Auth is an equal to now and the art ID is equal to this new ID value thats being put on the users collection
and will validate new data that has children.
Make sure that each new user begins with the properties name and Avatar.
And once again or validate these children for each user thats added We want to validate name so we can
grab the name roll that we had above or the name we shall lets added and paste it down here within users
and will provide the same role for Avatar.
You could change the length to your own custom value say 5 or 6 if you'd like but for now just hit publish.
Make sure we don't have any errors with any of our rules.
And so now we've locked down our database.