If we don't feel in any of the inputs on our register form but still hit the submit button we're constantly
going there from firebase and we shouldn't allow this to happen.
We should be able to send the form data through our back and without first making sure that all the
fields are filled out.
So some form validation within Hammill submit by adding a conditional where we call the function is
form valid and only if the form is valid will we allow the data to be sent off to firebase from the
form.
So create This is for a valid function and I'll check for a couple of things.
First we'll execute a function called is forment to make sure all of our inputs are filled out.
If not we'll throw an error.
Otherwise we'll check to make sure our passwords are valid.
And if that's not the case we'll throw an error in that event to.
But if both of these conditions are met well say that our form is valid and return true allowing our
form data to be sent off to firebase we'll first create this form empty function
and within is form empty which will create underneath is form valid wants to take each of the input
values that are stored within our state object we can pass in where we call is form empty entire state
object.
And then within the parameters the structure using object is structuring each of the individual values
for our inputs and check to make sure that there is a value provided to each of them.
We'll do that with a conditional where it'll take the length of the value that was typed in and turn
it into its opposite boolean value.
So if we have a length of zero for any one of these inputs we will return from this function true indicating
that our form is not entirely filled out.
And to throw an error when we return true or more is form empty function within is 1 valid will create
a variable called errors that are equal to an empty array and an error variable
will assign our air variable to an object with a property of message with the text fill in all fields.
And we want to set the state to put that error on an errors array within state or add that property
to our state object
and update that by taking the errors the empty errors array and concatenating the error object that
we just created.
And then we want to return false indicating that we should not execute handles submit.
Then let's create a function.
I will check to see if our passwords are valid.
Who also passed the state object to is password valid but instead of destructuring all the values of
the input values will just grab password and password confirmation.
And here we first want to check the length of both of these values
if either password or password confirmation have a length of less than 6.
We're going to return false indicating that our passwords aren't valid so the passwords that we provide
to the forum need to be at least six characters in length.
We also want to check to make sure that our password and password confirmation values are the same.
Otherwise we return true if both of those conditions are met and then to cover the error case for a
password isn't valid.
We'll assign the variable to an object the property of message and the text of password is invalid.
And once again set the state where we set the errors array in state and concatenate error on onto our
errors array and return false at the end of that as well.
Now we can save our changes and test this out test out our validation.
If we had to submit I don't see any firebase err on the console anymore.
We'll head to our reactive tools and navigate to our register component pull up the state in our air.
We see that we have one new element.
It's an object with a message of fill in all fields.
And now if we fill in the entire form but our password confirmation doesn't match our password we get
the error message password is invalid.
And also if our passwords match but they're both too short we get the same error message we don't fill
out all the fields we get fill in all fields again.
So it looks like our form validation is working well.
Finally we want to display any errors from our form validation to our user so they know what's going
wrong and sending off the form will create a function called display errors to do that.
It'll take the errors or say that we haven't stay.
We use the map method to map over those errors or take the error value as well as the index of the element
that we're iterating over and return a set of tags.
Put the key prop on the opening tag set equal to the index and we'll show them the message with the
interpolated value error message so underneath our form component we're going to display any errors
first by checking to see that we have some errors within our errors.
Make sure that the length of the error is greater than zero.
If that's the case we're going to show our user a message component with this ere prompt to give it
some air styling within it.
They'll be an age three the text of air then we'll call our display arrows function underneath where
we'll pass in the air xray from St..
Now if we do structure errors from stay within our render we can make the path of this a bit shorter.
Or you can just check to see that airs at length is greater than zero and pasand errors to display errors.
We'll save that head back to our app.
We hit submit.
We can see our air message underneath telling us to fill in all the fields
and if we fill in our form such that our password and password confirmations don't match.
We'll also get our password air.