We have improved our register form by adding error handling and form validation.
But there's a couple of small areas to take note of when you try to register with a new user.
It's possible to hit submit twice and as a result our users registered but we get in there and we're
also not clearing any errors when we have a successful registration to fix both of these errors.
We'll head back up to handle submit or roll first move event up prevent default above the one valid
conditional.
And before we reach out to firebase we're going to set the stage.
We're going to clear the air.
And we're going to set a loading property to True.
Now we haven't created this looting property yet so we'll do that within our state object.
Loading will initially be set to false and will set it to true only when we're in the process of registering
a user and under the then part of our promise.
We're going to set loading back to false.
And if we have any errors in the catch part we'll set loading to post there as well since our promises
resolved although unsuccessfully and here we can also set our errors object or heir's array and concatenate
the air that we're getting onto it.
Now with the structure or loading property from state within render.
And head down to our submit button.
We first want to set the class the button according to the loading value.
So we'll give the class name value a ternary Riddel check to see if loading said to true.
If so we'll give it class of loading which will put a loading spin on within the button will also give
it the disabled prop where if loading is true or button will be disabled and the user in the process
of being registered won't be able to click on the submit button twice.
Now if we head back to our form and we have an error
for example our password is invalid.
If we fill this out correctly and hit submit again we can see that our errors cleared or button is disabled
and we see our loading spinner.
And now you see our new user information and of course if we hit submit again we get our air from firebase
But now that error is put within our error message to Additionally if an error is coming from incorrectly
filling out a given input we can give that input and error class error silent.
We'll do that in the class named Propp.
We will iterate over all the errors using the or a method and for each error element will take the message
property of the error object and convert the text to lowercase just to normalize it.
And we'll see using the includes method whether the text for the error includes the name of the input.
So in this case to see if it includes the text email.
If so we'll give it an air A-Class.
Otherwise we won't give it any class.
This provides a nice visual indication for our user about where the error is coming from what they need
to change.
So if we try to register a new user but supply and email address that's associated with an already registered
user you'll get an error about it.
Now I can see visually our e-mail inputs red indicating that something is wrong with it.
And we can apply this to our other inputs as well.
Well in order to make this a bit easier we'll create this handle input error function and this function
will take a couple of things.
First the errors array and then the input name the name of the input that we're on we can grab all of
the code that we had to determine the class name for our e-mail input.
And just replace that with a call to handle input error.
We passed down the errors array and the name of the input email as a string.
And now we can paste all that we copied with and handle input air and make sure that we return the class
based on the value that it computes and instead of checking to see whether this error messages includes
just e-mail will pass and the input name parameter to it.
Now we can call this function for the class names of both password and password confirmation.
We'll give both of them an input name of password.
We could also do the same for the username if you like if you're creating any username specific errors
to test this out.
We'll try registering a new user but whose password password confirmation values aren't the same.
We hit submit we see our password is invalid and both of our password inputs are highlighted red to
indicate an error with them.