When we register new users we know that we get back some automatically created user data from firebase
for the purposes of our app.
We want to change some of these values that we register a new user and take a look at that user object.
You see first that display name is set to nil.
We want to use display name to store the user's username in or out.
Also photo you are out set to know.
This is where you want to store the user's avatar image.
So back in the gun statement we're registering our user or comment out said state and take the created
user object and on the user property we have this update profile method which will use to give display
name the value of the user name input.
And pass a Eurail to photo euro or get an avatar from Gravatar dot com slash Avatar.
And then we will imports a function called M.D 5 from the package M.D 5.
Now M.D 5 is usually used to hash messages we'll be using it to create a unique value to provide to
the Gravatar dot com slash Avatar your L and all take the user email from created user that user dot
email and it's a unique value as required by firebase pass it to M.D 5 and then after we interpret this
value we'll add questionmark d equals Identica on to get a avatar image generated for each new user
Wow the then statement after that and within then or sets date and are loading property to False.
After that we'll catch any errors in the catch block.
As well as those errors and state by concatenating onto the arrows array the air that we're getting
as well as loading to false there
will save all that.
We'll head back to our out and we'll try registering a new user
and we'll take a look at the user data that comes back from firebase
as we can see we have display name set to the user guy that we provided and in 40 we should have an
avatar image with our Gravatar dot com you are el.
If we save this object as a global variable in our consul
then we access the Hodo Ural path
we copy that link and open it in a new town should be able to see our avatar image that was generated
by Gravatar
And now that we're adding a user name and Avatar to the user that's just been registered.
Within the then statement we're setting the loading property of state to False.
We're going to instead call function save user repassing the created user and added then block we're
in the body we're just going to log users saved.
So as the then indicates this will be a promise and only panel submit will create or save user function
it'll take created user and it won't save user to save the users that we're registering to our database.
So back in our firebase console click on the database tab on the left hand side and I'll scroll down
to where we have the option for real time database will click on Create database.
We want to start in test mode to allow all reads and writes for the time being then click on unable
to set up or firebase database.
We can click on this plus button and we can take a look at what this collection will look like for our
users.
We'll have an array of users for every new user that registers will have a unique ID for them.
And on that ID we're going to include information about the user that just registered their display
name value their name that they provided as well as their photo euro which will be Gravatar accomplish
something.
And so it will look something like this or will have the users collection an array of users with their
unique IDs and within them their specific information.
But we'll delete that sample collection and go back to our code editor to actually implement that
who save user.
We're going to return a user's or is going to need to create a users of property and state.
Is going to reference the collection that we just took a look at will be at the path firebase start
database that ran with a string of users or this all reference that collection of data where all of
our users will be added
and we can put a child piece of data on it with the child method.
We want to put their I.D. and we'll get that with created user data user ID if you're interested in
taking a look at what that is when we get our user information back upon registering.
We have this unique ID value at the very bottom of the user object.
That's what we're going to be setting as a child and our users collection and our database.
And we're going to use the set method to set an object on that unique ID for our user not have a name
property which will reference the user name and created user that user that display name and an avatar
property created user to user dot photo euro.
The two things that we just set on our user data object will save that
we'll try registering another user
submit.
We can see our user data created by firebase our users saved log that we provided to the then statement
after executing our save user function and updating the profile of the created user.
So if we head back to our database we see this new users collection with a unique ID for the newly created
user as a child and the user's Avatar and name within.