If we take a look at our loggin component by clicking on the log and link you can see that it's not
been built out at all.
So we'll move on to creating that.
But first I want to go to the head or component within register and change that to as each one and set
of each two just to make the header a bit bigger for appearances sake.
We'll copy all the markup within the registry component and then log in will select everything and paste
in what we copied from Register will change all of our code as needed.
Remove the import from the 5 we'll change the name of the class from register to log in.
We'll remove the properties username password confirmation and user's ref from St..
Well get rid of the validation functions and get rid of is form valid as well as is form empty and is
password valid.
Or remove the firebase promise or call and create user with email and password within our handle submit
we'll get rid of the call to save user so the save user function and we'll remove the structured values
for user and password confirmation and render.
And now we'll change the header to the color Violet.
Change the name of the icon within the header to code branch color of that to Violet and the text within
the header to log into dev chat.
Going to get rid of the user name input
as well as the password confirmation input change the button to Violet
we're going to change the message at the bottom to include the text.
Don't have an account.
Questionmark and link them to the register out with a text of register and at the end.
Make sure to export the logon component.
We save all that we go to log in can see our new form here.
The first thing we'll do within log in is we'll change the call to form valid to pass in start state
and create a new form value function.
We're going to structure the email and password properties and within the return we're just going to
check to make sure that there are values for email and password or using the end conditional and underneath
the set state and handle submit going to once again use the off function in firebase and then call sign
in with email and password which will take the e-mail value and password values and state however then
block which will give us the signed and user data from the user that just signed in.
So a log that
will make sure to catch any errors or catch block logged with canceled out error
and we'll set the state in particular we'll set the heirs property on state and concatenate the error
message on to our heirs array and set loading to false
save that had back and see if we can log in with a user that we've already registered with
type in their email or password.
If we pass an incorrect password you can see we're still getting our error message
if we type in the correct password.
We see our user information within the console.