We'll be using the component library semantic you react for our markup and styles within our project.
You can find the documentation for it at re-act semantic dot com.
We're using their usage section in order to finish setting it up.
We've already installed the semantic you react dependency.
Now I just need to bring in the related styles so I'll grab this import to the semantic UI stylesheet.
Can either copy as you see it here or go to their documentation to grab it or import it within index
not Jap's and or move the import to index at CSSA and remove the file entirely from our project files.
And onto the save index.
Yes we should see the rules from that style sheet applied to our app.
You can see that the text is a bit different a bit smaller.
And now we'll use semantic you react in order to build out our register component or import a number
of components from me and you I react in particular will grab the grid form segment button had her message
and icon components will begin with the grid component as the parent component grid will be used to
structure content within our components give it the proper text align center and vertical line middle
to center everything on the x and y axes will give it a Grid column component to put everything within
a column in our grid.
We'll give it a small prob with the rule of Max with set to 450.
So the max with this column will be 450 pixels.
We'll have our head component which will set as an H2 as H2 tags.
Give it a proper icon a color orange text a line set to center again to center all the text within it
we're going to include an icon within the header and the name for it will be a puzzle piece.
You can find all the icons the available icons within the documentation to semantic UI I give it a color
orange and the text will be register for def.
So Deb chat will be the name of our app.
Underneath the head will have a form component with the size of large so it can set the size for a number
of these semantic UI components and we'll include a segment so we can put together all of the related
content and a proper stack to stack everything on top of one another.
And within this form we'll have a number of inputs.
So we'll have a form input with the proper fluid to make the input the entire width of the parent component
name of user name iconv user position the icon to the left and give it a placeholder text user name.
And as with any input we need to add an onchange handler so offset that to the function handle change
which will eventually use to update state according to the value typed into this input.
But for now we'll just leave that empty as well as an empty state object will also give it a type of
text to indicate that we're just going to be typing text for this username and put you can copy that
entire input component pasted in right underneath.
We'll change the name to email the icon that will have to mail the placeholder to e-mail address.
This is where users will type in their e-mail address to register and the type of it will be email or
set up some really basic a simple five validation.
We'll paste it in again.
Give it a name of password icon a block a placeholder a password and the type where it will be password.
Now will copy this password and put and paste it underneath and this will be the password confirmation
input her users to be able to confirm the password that they supplied given the name of password confirmation
and icon of the placeholder password confirmation.
Two words and we'll leave the type as password then we'll have a button that users can click onto submit
their form.
You know the color of orange be fluid and the size will be large underneath the form will have a message
which will tell users or ask them if they're already a user or import the linked component from the
pack Packers re-act Rotterdam.
So if they're already use or if they've already registered before we'll give them a link so that they
can log in go to the log in page so the link will be to slash log in and the text will be logged in
can save all of that.
If we take a look in our browser
can see our register form although it's kind of up at the top.
We need to bring this down to the middle of the page.
We'll do that by going to Apter.
CSSA and adding a rule for aist him our body and this app class that will create will give it a height
of 100 view height.
So take up the entire height of the browser give the background the tax code easy and the padding of
one end around it will provide that class name that we just created the rule that we just created to
our grid component class name of app.
If we refresh we can see the backgrounds changed our form is centered and if we click on the log and
link redirect to log in page.