Let's add functionality to our register form so a user can fill it out and register for our app.
We'll begin with the handle change function which we attach to every input via the onchange handler.
We're going to pass through the event object and using the data on this object whenever there is a change
event we're going to set the stage and we want to set properties within state that correspond to these
name attributes that we set for each of the inputs.
So to get the name of a given input or users type again we'll do it with event that target that name
and the value that the user has typed into a given input all access with event or target value and within
state we want properties that correspond to each of the values that we set to the Name property so it
will be user name email password and password confirmation.
We'll set those all to an empty string and back in our app we can right click and hit and Spack to open
our console.
You can alternatively hit Option Command and Jay or I will hit the arrow up at the top and go to our
re-act Deb tools will then search for our register component.
Now I can see the state object with all the properties that we put in there.
We type into each one of these inputs.
We should see the corresponding property in state updated.
Now we want to make it so a user can hit submit when they filled out all the fields and actually register
themselves
with first touch on an optional step that we can perform.
We can do structure all of the values from the state object and pass them down to our individual inputs
will grab the user name email password and password confirmation from state using object destructuring
and we'll pass each of those to their respective input via the value prop.
The purpose of doing this of passing the value of a given input back to its input component is that
when we set the state.
For example if we set the state of each one of these properties to say an empty string we can clear
any of the values that a user has typed in to their form that allows us to clear our form and on the
form component we're going to add an on submit handler and we're going to connect it to the handle submit
function that we're going to create right underneath handle change.
It will also take the event and we're going to call a method on event they we're getting called prevent
default to prevent the default action sending a form which is to reload the page.
And now we want to import firebase from our firebase file includes all of our configuration and the
imported packages the sub dependencies and in particular we're going to want to grab and use the firebase
slash off dependency.
So we're going to get firebase from two levels of
so now we can use it within handle submit.
We're going to first call the author method to make use of all the authorization tools and then we're
going to create user with email and password and to this all we need to do to register a user is to
pass in the value that a user supplied for the e-mail input and the password input.
From state start state or email mistaught state or password.
And since this is a promise we can within a then statement we can get back the user that's created by
firebase.
And for now we'll just log that as created user.
And after that then we'll catch any errors with this catch statement we'll pass through any errors to
a simple console that error will save that Adoor consul from our dev tools and we'll sign up register
with a user write a username email password and password confirmation.
And when we hit submit we see the con. we're getting an error.
We're getting a 400 air and in particular we're getting a message that tells us that the given sign
and provider is disabled and that we need to enable it within the firebase console.
So we're trying to sign in using the sign in provider to enable that we need to go to the authentication
tab within our firebase console and click on this button set up sign in method.
And appear next to the email and password provider.
Click on the pencil icon and we'll hit enable for this to enable sign ups with email and password.
Now we can see the status for it is enabled can head back to our app and try submitting this form one
more time to register our first user.
It looks like it's successful.
We get an object back with a number of properties additional user info credential operation type.
All of the user info that we provided will be within this user property and includes a bunch of other
stuff as well.
So it includes the email that we provided to it as well as stuff like phone number photo you are all
refreshed token a number of things we're making use of a number of these properties and later sections
and updating them for a given user.
And if we take a look at
back in firebase in our panel the users tab we can see we have our first user here in this user table
with the identifier the provider when it was created when the user signed in and their user ID.