Now work on adding notifications to our public channels when we're in one channel but see that other
messages are added to a channel that we're not on we'll begin by going to our channels component
and we'll first create a property in St. Paul Channel initially set to now also create a message is
read referencing our messages collection
as well as notifications property set to an empty array.
We'll head down to change channel and with the channel that's being passed and are going to set the
state and update the channel value that we just created.
We'll execute a new function within our ADD listeners function that'll take the ID of every channel
that's added to the channels ref will snacky this function will be called add notification listener
Ill accept snap key as Channel ID.
This will allow us to take the messages.
Channel ID as a child on it and listen for any value changes meaning listen for any new messages added
to any of our channels and if we have a value for that channel property within state that we just created
if the user has changed the channel they're on.
Going to show them the number of messages that are new and the other channels that they're not on.
By executing this function handle notifications will take the channel ID.
The idea of the channel and state the notifications are and state and the entire snap
and now I'm creating this channel notifications function will call these parameters channel ID the current
channel ID the one stored in state notifications and snap or first create this last total variable setting
equal to zero then will iterate over the notifications array that we're getting from state use find
index to do so.
We want to find index value for an array element within the notifications or a which has an id property
that's equal to channel ID.
So we want to see if we have any information about a given channel.
So if we don't if the index is equal to negative one from fine index we want to push a new array element
onto our notifications right.
And this will be an object which will first contain an id property set to channel ID a total value set
to snapshot some children to get the total number of messages for a given channel.
Last known total the same value and account property set initially to zero but which we'll update to
get our final total of notifications.
So now if we do have an index value for a given channel one to make sure it's not equal to the current
channel ID.
And now we'll update the last total value using the total value from the given array element then we'll
get the most recent number of messages for a given channel with snapped on some children subtracted
by the last total.
And if it's greater than zero if there is a new message or multiple messages added to a given channel
we're going to update the Count property for a given element with snap that children minus last total.
So that should be the number of new messages.
We're given channel and then at the very end we'll update the last known total with snapchat name children.
And finally when the message listener has been executed after firing off a message we've run our conditional
we want to update the notifications right and state so save that head back to our app and test this
out.
First we need to make sure that we switch to a different channel so that we have a channel value within
our state.
Remember that our handle notifications function will only run if we have a non-null value for our channel
then state by switching to another channel will navigate to channels component in depth tools.
Take a look at the notifications right now if we add a new message to the second channel I can see a
new element was added to the array an object with the properties total last known total.
The idea of the channel as well as the count and the counters set to zero since the current channel
ID and the channel ID are the same.
We're not going to see any notifications.
Since we're on that same channel and we added the message ourselves out when we changed the channel
that we're on we want to execute a function called Clear notifications and clear notifications.
Will remove any notifications that we're getting for a channel that we're currently on if we see that
there are new messages and we take a look at those messages obviously we don't want to be notified about
them anymore.
So once again take the notifications or iterate over it using find index method We'll check to see if
there is an id property whose value is equal to the channel that we have stored in state it's ID value.
And if it finds a positive index number for it it's not equal to negative 1.
We're going to copy the notifications reinstate inserted equal to a variable updated notifications and
we'll use the array spread operator in order to copy that array will take updated notifications and
select an element based on that index grab its total value of notifications and we want to update this
one to update it by taking the notifications or in-state selecting an element based on the index value
that we found and updating it with the last known total value.
And then we want to take the Count property and set that equal to zero.
Then finally we want to settle on a vacation and stay with our new updated notifications variable.
Now that we've done all this work for getting the count of new messages and other channels we want to
display it we'll do that within display channels or execute a function called get notification count.
It'll take the channel that's being iterated over and if the value returned is true or truth the are
going to display a label component from semantic UI with the color red and within it will interpolate
the number of new messages with getting notification count once again passing in the channel.
So make sure to bring in the label component from semantic UI and we'll create this new function
and get notification count takes the channel being iterated over will create account variables that
initially zero will take the notifications are in state no user for each to iterate over it for each
notification element.
We want to check to see first of all if the ID on the element is equal the channel got ID.
If so we'll update the count variable the Count property on the notification element.
And lastly we want to check to make sure that the account number is greater than zero.
If so or return that number and this way that as the number of new messages within this label component
next to our channel So save all that and optionally if we want to get notifications about new messages
added to other channels without having to first switch the channel we can within the first channel function.
Set the stage set the channel properly and states to first channel then work my terminal.
We're going to deploy my app with the now Seelye to test this out and once it's been deployed going
apace the deployed you're all that I get into a new town
and bring it to the side so I can log in with a different user and cast out our notification functionality.
So switch to the Riak channel type in a new message.
Once I hit ad reply you can see the notification for one new message added to the Riak channel for my
first user by Taipan.
Now to another message.
And see that's updated to two.
And the web server by ADD or apply.
You can see that notifications added to the deployed euro.
And if we visit both of these channels you can see that the number the count of new messages is cleared
out.
When we visited.