Nelse out or a Moji picker when they click on this plus button next to your message input in order to
add emerges to our messages to the message form and up at the top we'll import a couple of things from
the package Moji mark or grab first the emoji picker and emoji index and we want to bring in the related
tiles for that for the picker from a Moji Mark ICSA us slash emerging markets USS then we'll head down
to our message and put in on the label Propp will add an on click to the button within it set to handle
toggle picker for this new function which will create underneath and key down
will toggle the emoji picker that we brought in.
So we'll set the property on state called a Moji picker will be the opposite value of Moji picker so
we'll set that within state to initial value of falls and then we'll head back down
and restructure this new emerging Pichler property from state within Rander and will now show the Moji
picker component conditionally based on the value of this emoji picker value and state.
So have our picker component with a set of a Moji set to Apple.
So have the Apple M-O GS will attach a class name to it of Moji picker which will create will give it
a title value of pick your Moji and will include an emoji point next to the title.
Now let's create or emoji picker class and applets VSS or you just want to set position to absolute
will save both of our files.
And we'll click on the plus button.
Now I can see our Moji picker component.
So we have a big set of images to pick from.
We have our title pick your emoji and these are all of the apple emojis.
You can pick another set if you like but we'll stick with Apple
and we'll add another prop to the picker component called on select.
This will allow us to add a new emoji to the message that we're adding so that all reference a new function
called handle added Moji it'll take the emoji that we're selecting from the emoji picker.
And within the function or Herst create a variable called Old message to reference the message value
and state and will create a new message variable which will execute a function called colon to Unicode.
We'll take within template literals the old message and interpolate the old message value and put a
space at the beginning of it and in between our next value which will interplay of emerging dark Colon's.
So referencing a Kolins property on the Moji object that we're passing this function we're going to
set the state will set the message property to Cornu message value and close the Moji picker by setting
the Moji picker to false.
Now I'm going to paste in the code for the colon to Unicode function.
It basically takes our message and converts that emoji Colon's value to a Unicode using the emoji index
tool that we imported.
So you can copy the code as you see it here or get it and the final code attached to this video.
And now when we save all the changes we made and we try adding a message like hello and selecting an
emoji you can see it show up within our input and very quick on our reply.
You can see it's added to the channel that we specified.
Now you'll notice that if we select an emoji we don't have the input focused.
After we do so so we want to fix that to focus the input again after we select an emoji.
I heading down to our input once again
and we'll put a ref on it.
Which one is it going to include an inline function or pass through this no value and set it equal to
this message input ref value which we're putting on our class.
So now we can reference it and use it to focus our input.
So then handle added Moji we're going to add a set time out or within the body of the set time.
We're going to call this our message input wrapped up focus to focus the input after 0 milliseconds
so that it runs immediately after our set state.
Then on the label
for the button that we supplied to the label prop of our input we're going to change the icon value
to a turn Airey if a Moji picker's set to true.
We're going to give it an icon of clothes otherwise an icon of ADD and to the content Propp will set
up a similar to an area where if a Moji picker set to true will have the text of clothes or the text
of no.
If it's false We'll save our file once again.
We'll head back to our and see how this works.
Now
we'll toggle the emoji picker We'll select an emoji we see are close text and now our input is refocussed.
After adding an emoji so you can add more text without having to click on the input.
And of course we can add a reply as usual.