Whenever a new message is added whether we've added the message or someone else's out the message we
always have to scroll to the bottom of the channel in order to see it.
It would be a much nicer behavior if we had an auto scroll down to the bottom whenever a new message
was added.
So to implement this within our messages component will go all the way down to our common group.
And before the closing tag will add a div which will have Areff.
Once again we use an inline function we'll call this ref messages and
and in order to whenever a new message is added scroll to the bottom of the channel to see that message
we'll use the component did update lifecycle method.
And even though we won't be using either of the parameters we have access to previous props and previous
state whenever our component updates
and if we have a raft of messages and we will execute a function called scroll to bottom.
So this will scroll our channel to the end
and we'll take the messages Endora and we'll use a method on it called scroll interview.
And within that we can put an object where we can set the behavior of the scroll and or set it to smooth
to smooth scroll.
This ref interview was no scroll to the div at the very bottom of our messages component.
And as you'll see this will be executed whenever our component updates.
For example we add a message.
We immediately go down to the bottom and it moves across the bottom very nicely and it all smooth scroll
to the bottom in any event whenever we have a new message added by us or another user.
Or if we see that another user is typing within the same channel
if I open my deployed application and log in with the different user and start typing
I'm taken down to the bottom both when the other users typing as well as when the message is added.