Whenever a chat loads or whenever we reload the page we see within our messages area a blank area until
our messages are loaded.
So this isn't a very good user experience.
We want to tell our user that our messages are in the process of being loaded and we can do that with
this message as loading property that we're setting in the state and our messages component.
So as our messages are being loaded We'll show this skeleton component that will create within it this
will be a seamless functional component and it'll first contain a div with a class of skeleton within
the div will have a number of issues with their own respective classes.
First with the class of Scott and Avatar next day with the class of Skelton author and then I did with
the class of skells and details for export a skeleton component and then we'll head to Atlanta DSS and
create the rules for each of these classes.
We're going to section that we'll call skeleton dodgiest.
So begin with the skeleton class
this main class will have a position of relative overflow set to a hidden it'll have a height of 40
pixels and margin bottom of 10 pixels and we'll give it a pseudo element of after for additional styling
with a content set to an empty string that displayed a block or give it a position of absolute top will
be set to zero left zero with 50 percent a height of 100 percent
and will animate it with this sweep animation which will last two seconds and will be an infinite animation
and will include a background image which will be a linear gradient the values to left transparent and
R-Ga. of the five 255 255 and opacity of 0.4 and final value of transparent
and Ozalp a keyframes with the name of Swee as the name of the animation suggests will slowly sweep
it across the skeleton div first by putting the animation on the far left hand side of the div so that
0 percent will give it a translate X of a negative 100 percent at 50 percent of the animation.
When it's halfway through we'll set translate X to 150 percent sweep it over to the far right of the
div and then at 100 percent or term translate X back to negative 100 percent.
So this animation will take place over the course of two seconds and within our skeleton div will have
her skeleton Avatar class with a height of 35 pixels with 35 pixels a border radius of three pixels
a background color of R-GA fifty fifty seven fifty seven and opacity of 0.3.
So this will be the outline of the avatar for a given message.
For Skelton author class it will have the same background color value.
So we can copy that.
It will have a with of 120 pixels a height of 10 pixels a border radius of three pixels.
Position will be set to absolute will give it a bottom of thirty pixels.
Aleft of 40 pixels and a rate of zero.
Then for a skeleton details
we'll give it a background color of the same value as Skilton author and skells an avatar a height of
20 pixels border radius of three pixels.
Position.
Absolute again or bottom will be set to five pixels left forty pixels right.
Twenty pixels.
And now we'll head back to messages and we'll make sure to import our skeleton component.
So with the skeleton component as the name suggests it provides a kind of outline for each of our messages
that are being loaded to describe to our user beforehand what they'll see in the UI.
So now within render we can structure messages loading from our state object and within common group
or comment group component will execute a new function called display messages skeleton and more passed
down messages loading to this function so if messages loading is set to true and will pass it to display
messages gotten as loading.
If loading is true we're going to display first re-act fragment.
And since the Skelton component represents one message being loaded but we don't want to display just
one skeleton but a number of them to fill up the messages section.
We can use a trick where we use the array constructor passed a value of 10 to get 10 elements spread
that result into a new array.
Use the map method or we only use the index parameter in the return.
We return our skeleton we're now iterating over a skeleton component 10 times.
We'll give it a key proc set equal to I which is why we're using it and the map function and if floating
set to false if we're not loading any messages we're going to return.
No from display message skeleton.
So now enter AFP as our messages are being loaded with display Skelton component.
The show uses the outline of each of the messages before they're actually displayed in the UI.