In the past we've always had to add messages to channels by clicking on the Reply button in order to
create an alternative for our users to make sending messages a bit easier.
Let's set up a key shortcut so that users can just press a succession of keys and very quickly send
off a message.
We'll do this within the message form component and then the handle key down function or pass through
the event and on the event we'll check to see that they're pressing the control key with event control
key as well as the return key by checking to see if event DocI code is equal to 13.
If that's the case if they're pressing both those keys at the same time we'll then send the message
to save that back to her first try sending a message the old way.
So pick an emoji and then hit reply.
You see our message now can just type the message and hit control and enter and our messages added as
well.
So this just provides an alternative for users.
It's very convenient if you're sending a lot of messages if you're looking to make your own key shortcuts.
There's a very nice tool at Kiko dot info that will tell you the specific key code of any key that you
type in.