Within our chat we'll have a number of channels that users will be able to add messages to.
We'll add the channels component underneath our user panel component in our side panel then the side
panel file.
We had channels underneath the user panel component and add a file for it in the side panel folder of
the top of channels will import re-act from react.
And this will be a staple component we'll call this class channels
will have its render in return and will make sure to export the class at the bottom
but then the return are going to include this menu menu component menu up manual be a child of the main
menu component thats within our side panel and we will make sure to import menu from semantic you react
and on the opening tag sort of outcrop with padding bottom set to two m's.
So give it some padding on the bottom.
And then you a manual have a menu item within it.
That will contain a spam with an icon so grab that from our import as well.
Or icon will have a name of exchange.
And on the right hand side is Icon will have the text channels.
So this will basically be the heading for our channels component.
Then underneath the spam will have a set of parentheses which will include the number of channels that
we currently have.
So create a state object had a channel's property which will be initialized to an empty array and will
the structure of the channel's property from state within or render
we're going to get the number of channels
using Rollings property.
We will interpolate channels that length into the right hand side of that we'll have an icon the name
for that will be added
then underneath the menu item will eventually show all of our channels which will iterate over.
So I'll just add a comment there for now.
And back with inside panel import channels from dot slash channels.
Since it's in the same Polder say both those files
backed her out.
Now I can see our channels Hetter channels text as well as the number of films that we have.
And in order to space out the title from the number of channels we can add this set of curly braces
and double quotes with the space in between to space out the text from the number of channels.