We want users in or out to be able to add new channels by clicking on this ad icon and when they click
on this icon We'll show them a model which will allow them to provide a name for their channel as well
some details about it to create a mobile component will import it from semantic UI
This will be our ad channel mobile
and on the opening tag of our mobile.
We had some props.
We'll get some basic styling with the basic prop.
We use the open prop in order to target toggle the visibility of our motile.
We'll do that using a property in state called motile will initially be set to false and we can do structure
from our state object in our render function.
So pass that to open if we set that to true we'll be able to see our model and we'll have an enclosed
Propp which will be set to a function called Close modal where all it will be irresponsible for doing
is setting the model property within state to false.
So again this will set the open property false and hide our modal
will add a header to our model with modal dot header.
You know the text of our channel includes some content
and in our model we'll have both the form component and a couple of input components.
So will outperform and the form will have a couple of foreign fields and these will include our input
components give it the proper fluids to take up the full width
of a label attribute with the person in the name of channel a name attribute of channel name and an
onchange set to this start handle change.
We want to update the state object according to the Name property of the input that a user is typing
in so past an event to handle change.
Was that the state set the property according to eventa target that name and the value of that or B
event or Target or value
or had a state property of channel name and another one of channel details so have another input.
With the name of channel details right underneath our first input will copy the entire form field and
pasted in underneath that name to channel details and the label will be
about the channel
underneath the modal content.
We'll have this Modal actions area and this will include a couple of buttons or we can optionally add
a channel or cancel adding a channel so bring in the button component from semantic UI
the button will have a color prop of green We'll have the inverted prop include an icon with the name
of checkmark in the text of ADD we can copy this button and paste it in underneath.
With the color of red the name of remove and the text of cancell.
And since we're returning to components our menu component in our modal component we need to put everything
within a single component using reactant fragment.
This is a good way to group two components or multiple components to return just one component within
a file.
You can add an unclick on our ADD icon to open modal so also have a function called Open modal which
will change the modal prop in state to true
to show the model in Sabor channels file and back to your app will try opening a modem by clicking on
the icon that opens our ad channel model will head to our re-act dev tools
and search for the channels component
we'll type into our name of channel and about the channel inputs we can see corresponding properties
in state or updated.
But our cancel button isn't working we're going to have an unclick to our cancelbot and we'll set that
to reclose model function which will close the model if we want to cancel adding a channel
so we refresh our app we can open the model and host the model.