We have our users collection in our database.
Now we want to create a channel selection for every new channel that a user creates
collection of movie channels and all contain an array of unique IDs for each new channel that's added
and then Id contain the name of the channel that the user specified.
The details about the channel
the unique ID
as well as some meta information about the channel namely who created the channel so created by will
be an object that contains the name of the user.
It made the channel as well as their avatar
and we can add that to take a look at what our channels collection looks similar to so our channels
question will be composed of an array of unique ideas and within them the channel information that the
users created back in our
will create a handle submit function which takes an event recall prevent default on this event.
Will set up a conditional check to see that the form is valid its being submitted will take the state
object and if it is if that function returns true or log channel added
will create this validation function is form valid and what the structure the values that we need from
state channel name and channel details the property names corresponding to our two inputs will be updated
as the user types in we want to make sure that there are values for channel name and channel details
and or connect our handle submit and submit handler to the form
as well as to the ABBERTON with an on click
I can say this and test it out
well try adding a channel open or con..
We don't have any values in the inputs quick and nothing is added.
We don't see the logo channel.
But if we type in the certain inputs we see the log channel added so our Hindol submit works only when
we have a valid form.
Now replace the log with a function add channel
create or add channel function.
Northen and channel will be reaching out to firebase to create a new channel within the channels collection.
Import firebase from two levels up.
We'll create a channel in our state object.
Once again it will be the database module and will create RF channels within and channel will structure
the channels raw from state.
First we want to create a unique key for each new channel that's added so create a variable called Key
will take the channels raw and use the push method and get the key property from calling push should
give us a unique identifier for every new channel thats added or create a new object called new channel
ruleset.
The idea of it to key the key variable name will be channel name.
So will the structure that from St..
Also the structure channel details for details property
that we have are created by object which includes the user name as well as the avatar of these that
created this channel.
So to get this information we need to pass the current user Propp and current user information from
our side panel down to our channels so pass it down as current user and receive that in our state with
the property name user set up process Krant user.
Also the structure that then ad channel.
So now the path to users name is used up display name and for their avatar its user dot photo Eurail
And finally will take the channels are
you put a child on it of the key variable you use the update function to pass new channel onto that
key.
Then one could again and will set the stage to clear both the channel name and the channel details from
St..
You could also make both channel name and channel details controlled inputs if you'd like.
Nor close the model analog channel added at the end will catch any errors.
The simple cancel error.
Now we've got all that we can save both files.
You can test this out
try adding a new channel
called this save food.
Say it's a channel about food.
Try adding it real quick.
Looks like we get our logo channel added.
Seems like it was successful and back in our database we have our channels collection our unique identifier
for one channel that was added as well as all the information we specified name ID details and are created
by object.