We have our first channel added to our channels collection.
Now we want to get all of the channel data all the channels that users have added within our channels
component.
We'll do that by creating the component of Mt lifecycle method and putting within its a function called
Ad lessness.
So execute ad listeners when the component mounts and the ad listeners will first take an array and
them T-Ray called Loaded channels.
That's going to out a listener going to listen for each new child added to the channels.
RATH will take children from state use the on method and MUSSEN for every new child added were able
to get information about each child with the snap callback and will push the value of each.
Now onto the loaded channels array.
And for now we'll log loaded channels when all of those values are pushed onto the tray.
See what it looks like back in our app will reload the page.
Take a look at our console.
You'll see that we have only one value in this array.
For now our one channel if we add the new channel
and click on and can see we immediately get information about that new child that was added but new
piece of data that was added to our channels raw or move the log and instead set the state onto set
the channels part of data channels program state to loaded channels
then down at the bottom at the closing tag of our menu component.
Once you iterate over the channels that were getting with a function called display channels and all
the structured channels from state within our render and display channels.
Take all the channels that we have in state and check to make sure that the length of it is greater
than zero to ensure that we actually have some.
And if that's the case we're going to map over those channels and we'll call each element channel
and put them within a menu item the channel data that we're getting in on this menu item will set a
key or iterating over to channel ID and click which for now just be an inline arrow function where we'll
log all the channel data
and give it a name that to channel that name and the style with the opacity set to 0.7
within the menu item then the tags give it a hash mark and then interpolate the channel name of channel
the name will say that
take a look in our browser and we can see how our two channels are appearing here and when we click
on them we get all of the related channel data.