When we click on a channel we log the information about it but ideally we want to click on a channel
and put the channel information on global state on its own property and state to do so will first create
a new function called change channel
to accept the channel that we're clicking on
and we want to fire in action when we call this function with the name set current channel which takes
the channel data and puts the channel data on global state or place the console log within our display
channels function with change channel
and create this action.
We're setting the current channel in our redux state for first hand to the types file in our actions
folder and first we created some user action types.
Now we're going to create a set of channel action types.
First Channel action type we give them the same name of set current channel
and within our index
once again separate our user actions from our channel actions.
And so be interacting with a different part of our global state.
Export function called current channel looks up channel data no return an object with the type from
action types of said current channel our payload will consist of a property called current channel or
we'll put the channel data on it.
So within our reducers we're going to create a new reducer and sort of this user reducer which put information
on the user property of say we're going to create a channel producer for our channel data alone we'll
take the state and the action and I'll set up some initial state to call this object initial channel
state or initial channel state or consist of a current channel property set to no will have no channel
selected initially no set or state as the default value initial channels the default value of our state
will set up a switch statement or switching based on the type of the action.
And in the case that we have Bissette current channel action type or return an object in which we spread
all the initial values of the state and only change the current channel property of it according to
action that payload that current channel with the channel data that's coming in.
I made one small error with the clear user case we want to spread the state and not the initial user
state and in the default case for our channel producer we want to just return the state if we don't
have a match for any case.
We'll put the results of the Channel producer within combined reducers to a new property channel.
So all of our channel data will exist on this channel property of global state and back within channels
we can use our set current channel action.
We just need to import the connect function from re-act redux up with a top and then import the action
that we want to use so that current channel
and since we're importing that up at the top we also need to connect
and wrap our component with it.
Well said Matthysse to props to know and the structure or action from Matt dispatched to prop's.
So we'll save all of our files back in our app.
We take a look at our read ex-state.
Take a look at our state object you see that we have this new channel property with the sole property
of current channel set to know.
And if we click on the channel you can see that it's populated with our channel data.
So we're putting our channel data now on mobile state
if we select the other channel that we have.
You can see we get its channel data as well so able to switch between channels and alternatively put
the respective channel data on local state.