Are now able to put the channel in Google say when you click on it.
But when we load the page we're only calling the set user action.
We're not putting any channel in our global state when our page loads.
We have to actually click on it first.
We want to change this behavior.
We want to load a channel by default.
When our page floats
we create this we begin by going to our ad listeners function and where we're setting the stage we're
adding the loaded channels to our channels property and say we're going to add a callback function.
We're going to execute a function that will create called Set first channel
and Secrest channel will do just that.
I'll take the first channel in R.A. or channels or hey and put it on global stage.
We'll set a conditional to say if Purslow to put a personal property in state so that initially the
true say if this that state that first load and this starts date that channels the length is greater
than zero if it's our first time loading the page and if we have more than no channels we have a channel
we're going to call our set current channel action and pass in the first channel.
And how do we get this first channel.
We'll just take the channels or a from this state that channels and grab the first element and set that
equal to the variable first channel
and then upon doing that we want to set the state in order to set first load to false.
We can say that and back to our
You can see now set user and current channel are being called when our page loads so now we have our
first channel within state and we can still change our channel to another one.
However we're not displaying which channel is currently active.
We want to change this as well.
We want to displayed our user which channel has been selected who will then change channel.
We're going to execute a function who's going to take which channel we're passing to change channel
in order to set the active channels or to call this action an active channel.
We'll simply take the channel data for the channel that's being switched to and set the state and update
a property on state called active channel.
It will just take the ID of it
we need to create this active channel property
we'll set it to an empty string initially and then back where we're iterating over our channels with
display channels.
We'll add this active prop to our menu item to compare.
If the channel that's currently being iterated over if it's ID is equal to this that state got active
channel and if it is it'll provide an active class to it and highlight it.
When we get back to our app
when our page loads and we click on a channel you'll see that we have some indication of where we're
currently at which channel we're on over we're not displaying it for the first half that we land on
if we want to change that.
We want to show that the current channels active when we're calling said first channel you can call
that active channel as well and passen first channel.
And with that we're now setting the channel by default.
When our page loads in or displaying the channel that's currently active.