Relistening for any new channels added on our channels.
When our channels component mounts with the ad listeners function.
We also need to handle the case when our component announced for example go to a different route in
our app that we're removing those listeners that we set up so we're not listening for an event that's
not going to take place within the component will on Mt lifecycle method.
We're going to call the function remove listeners and we'll be able to remove this channel's ref listener
simply by calling the off method on it.
It's an important step that we need to take.
We'll do it with every one of the listeners that we'll set up and each of our components to make sure
that our refs and our child graphs of that listener are turned off by calling the off method on them.