Users can now log in or register with in or out and once they do we can see their user data and the
consul can see the loading say.
Now we want to take them somewhere once they're authenticated and particular to the app component which
is where our chat will live.
To implement this will go to index dot J.S. and we'll bring in firebase are going to be using a listener
from firebase which will be able to detect whether a user has recently logged in or registered within
our app and changed the route component to a staple component.
So will change constitute class a classroom will extend reactor component
we'll have a render function and will bring in everything that we previously returned all of the routes.
We'll bring that within our render function and just pop the return key word in front of that and as
I mentioned we're going to execute a listener.
We'll do that when this root component mounts we'll use the component mount lifecycle method for this.
So when our route component mounts we're going to run by based on our on our state changes as a listener
which is going to detect whether we have a user in our app and we'll set up a conditional say if we
have a user if fire bases detected the user are going to want to redirect them to our home route.
We'll do that with reactor Don using the history object.
This stopped prox history of push to the route route.
If we save that you can see in our consul we're getting this air cannot read Property push up undefined.
So trying to make use of the history object to redirect outside of our routes or first need the higher
order component with router from reactor at her dorm to put the history object within our root component.
So create a new variable called root with off and or wrap root with the with router higher order component
will also grab the router tags
and or wrap this new component that we just created.
Within render with router
so we can only redirect when or within a router.
No change the route that we're rendering to now with off to include the with router H.M.S..
So now we can redirect once we have a user.
Now if we go back to our page you can see we're currently on the component.
We go back to log in and try to visit log in but will immediately be taken back to to our Since we're
now logged in.
And if we go to register that listener will do the same or just redirect us.