Now that you've got the state changes listen or set up for authenticated we're always redirected back
to the app component which is where our chat will live.
If we log this user value that we have access to within our state changed and we take a look at our
console we can see that it's an object which includes all of our user information for currently authenticated
user
and in developing the chat portion of our app.
We're going to be creating a lot of components many of which are going to need to access this user data.
It'd be nice if we could execute a function the name for example of set user repassing the user data
and put all of that data on global state.
So any of our Riak components that want to make use of it can to do this will set up the state management
system redux within Exxon objects and or import a few packages to set that up.
One port the function creates store from Rydex we import the provider component from reactor docs as
well as the function composable dev tools in order to set up our redux dev tools extension.
Now to create our global say all we need to do is create a store variable and this will store the return
value from executing we create store function into that we just need to pass an empty function.
For now as well as composite dev tools and make sure to execute that function
to provide this global state this global store to all of our components we'll use the provider component
or wrap our router with it provider will provide our global state to any component that wants to use
it and will pass it down using the store proc will pass the store variable to it.
Now what we've set that up we take a look at our browser we can see our dev tools.
For redox is now going green.
We go to the redux dev tools extension within our console can see this interface which will use in order
to interact with our global state.
And currently it's empty because we haven't set up our state any of the properties on state or any of
the actions I will be using to interact with state.
We'll begin by creating an actions folder within our source folder and this will contain two files an
index file as well as a type's file and action types will be responsible for determining what type of
change we want to make to our global state within our types file we'll create our first type to be a
variable called set user equal to the string of the same name set user.
We'll put this as a variable and export it.
Since we're going to be using it in a number of files in the first place we'll use it is in this index
file that we created in our actions folder will import all of the exports all of the exported types
from our types file as an object called action types then we'll create our first action which will have
the same name set user but written in the camel case syntax and to this function will pass in the user
data that we'll be getting and from our action we want to return two things.
First of all the type and the type or turn is the type that we just created the set user type on or
action type object.
And then a payload.
So actions also be responsible for passing the data that our state needs to be changed with.
So on our payload object will have one property of current user set to the user data that's passed into
it.
Now in order to actually perform the change to state of setting the user are going to create functions
called reducers and they'll do that within this reducers folder and create just an index that just file
within it here we'll also need to import our action types from our actions folder in the types file
and the first reducer function that will create will be called user reducer because it will reduce all
of the user related data.
It'll take a state argument as well as the action that's coming in and within the body will set up a
switch statement where it will update state accordingly depending upon the type of action that's coming
in.
As we set with that type variable.
So in the case that this is a set user action the type of set user We're going to want to update state
where we first take the current user data that's coming from action that payload that current user the
user data that we put on the current user property in our set user action.
And we also want to set the property is loading to false which will create on our state.
And we also need to set up a default case in every reducer where if it doesn't match a given action
type all it's going to do is just return the state as it was and to state the state parameter we're
going to set a default value of initial user state.
So this is what our users say it will look like without any changes we'll create this as an object just
above our producer or our current user will be set to nil and is loading will be set to true by default.
Now we want our reduced functions to only operate on a certain part of state.
For example our user reducer should only modify our user property on the global state.
So create this variable called Root reducer and all it will use a function which will import from Redus
called combine reducers and combine reducers will allow us to determine what property on global state
a given reducer updates will include combine reducers and within the object that it takes we can determine
that user producer will be updating and put it state values on this user property.
And now once we have that we can export default this route reduce our variable
and or place our empty function within create store with reproducer to get our entire state object and
will make sure to import route reducer from the reducers folder will save all of our files and if we
refresh our app we take a look at our redux that toes and click on the state option.
You can see we have this one property of user and on the property current user property as well as is
loading.
So he successfully set up our first action action type and reducer in order to set our user data on
global say with the set user action will need the connect function from re-act redux.
And as the name implies connect allows to connect or read ex-state actions with a given re-act component.
So wrap route with Connect to execute it in a set of parentheses before wrapping route we have access
to first the global stays with the map state to prop's argument.
But we dont need any state so just pass in now and then we have this map dispatched to prop's argument
as the second argument.
And this is where we'll get our actions then all we need to do to get set user is to structure it from
the map dispatch to prop's object.
So all these structures say user and will import set user from the index file of the actions folder
and what connect and map does best to prop's will do is it will take this set user action and put it
on our prop's object of the component that we're wrapping with CONNECT.
So now so that user will be on this.
Got props.
If we save our index file
on our page reloads will execute the user action and our current user property on the user object is
updated to the value that we're getting from our on changed.
Listener.