Now that we've created the set user action as was our global state when we're authenticated and then
redirected from log into our app component our user data is put on our global state.
But since state updates are asynchronous and take a certain amount of time to resolve.
We're past the maps date to prop's function as the first argument to our connect function to get loading
data from our state object to see when the set user action is still being loaded.
We want to get the loading property and this will be located on our user property of state.
So the path of that will be state DOT user dot is loading and then maps it to prop's in mind the typo
should be maps to prop's going to return an object which will have a property name of exploding in our
path of state that user is loading to get the current value of that we can log the exploding property
has the name of the function suggests on our prop's object.
So we can do that with this type prop's that is loading.
You can see the current value of is loading when our route component is being mounted you can see within
our console when the components mounted it is true.
So in order to prevent our user from seeing a blank screen as this set user actions being executed we're
going to set up a ternary in our return statement and a check to see if this that process is loading
is true.
And if it is if it's still loading we're going to show a spinner component.
Otherwise we're going to show our app route and our app component.
So we'll create a spinner component within our source folder called spin or not Jarius import re-act
up at the top.
Integrate the spinner will use the loader component from Symantec.
You react.
This will be a status functional component with the same name of spinner and immediately return the
loader component well make sure to export it at the bottom
and we can set a number of props on this loader component.
First of all we can set the size or set that to huge and we can provide some text underneath that with
the content prop will provide the text of preparing chat and tell our users exactly what's taking place
then we import within an index such as spinner from dot slash spinner
and save both of those files.
If we head back to our app
we don't see anything.
So it looks like our spinner wasn't working when in fact it was working.
We were displaying it to our users while the action was being resolved.
We just couldn't see it.
So to make it visible will bring in the dimmer component to surround the loader component and this will
provide a dark background to our loader and give it the prop of active.
So now we reload the page we can see our loader and our text of preparing chat as our set user action
is being resolved.