Now move onto deploying or add to the Web will do so using the NPM package.
Firebase tools so enter terminal and the development server and it's all Firebrace tools as a global
package with the dash g flag.
You might need to put sudo in front of it according to your user's permissions and once it's installed
run the command Firebrace log in will be asked to log in to firebase using Google or.
And once it's done you run firebase in it to initialize our Firebrace project then the CLIA is going
to take us through a number of steps.
The first will be to choose which sealife features we want to set up for this folder and will select
both the database and storage options with our spacebar and so we use both of those in our project and
then hit Enter then we'll be asked to choose the firebase product that we want to deploy we select that
and then it'll ask which file should we use for our database rules.
We'll choose the default of database type rules that Jason as was the default for the storage rules
storage rules.
Jason what this will do what I will do Ozel bring in all the rules we specified in our firebase console
and put them as a Jason file within our project.
So very quick on database rules that Jason we can see all of the rules that we just set up in the past
couple of sections and the same applies to the storage rules file.
We'll head to this firebase to Jason file that was also added and we're going to provide some additional
configuration here to tell firebase hosting how to host our first will run the command NPM run build
to create a production version of our re-act up that should have taken all of our javascript files and
bundled them into this build folder for production and to deploy it out to the Web.
We need to add a configuration setting within our Harbi So Jason will add a property name of hosting
the adjacent object in which we're going to tell the Selye to look within the build folder and make
it the public folder that will deploy to the web once we've configured that or run firebase deploy and
deploy everything within our build folder.
And at the very end we'll tell us or hosting your show where we can find our out on the web will pay
said in to our browser you can see our starting up as usual.
We can log in the preexisting user Oregon register hit submit and see our app startup as usual or provide
a new message to show that we actually deployed our project and that is running live on the web.