Is move onto to a color panel.
We created this button that we'll be able to click on and we want to display a model to our users for
them to be able to choose the colors of their app.
So I want to create a kind of color picker or head of the color panel component.
We're going to bring in a modal component the icon components and label components from semantic UI
nuance of first and an on unclick to our button which will open a modal.
So first we want to create a state object
with a modal property set initially to false and we've covered this a number of times.
We'll create an open modal function where it will set the State of the modal property to True.
Copy that
will create a closed modal function which will set the modal property to False
and underneath the button will create our color picker model.
So this will consist of the modal component where basic styling will open according to the modal property
and stay cool.
The structure modal from St.
and all have an on close.
So to are close modal function
so intermodal Herse have a header the text to choose colors
then will have a content area.
And then add actions area
when actions will have two buttons.
The first the color green
proper inverted an icon within it with the name set to check mark with the text of saved colors.
Well copy that and paste another one in.
Underneath the color red the name of remove the icon and the text of cancell now within our modal content
area we want to show a color picker which will allow users to pick the color that they want for their
app.
We use the package re-act color for this which gives us a number of color pictures to choose from with
a number of different styles.
You can certainly choose any of the ones available that you see on their documentation page but I'm
going to choose the slider component that they have available so to import that up at the top.
Well grab slider picker from re-act color
and then we'll put that within our content area first with the label component or label it with the
text of primary color then we'll have our first lighter picker for the primary color of our app.
And then another label with the text of secondary color and another picker to choose the secondary color.
And once we save our files and take a look in our app at the moto by clicking on the button and our
color panel you can see both of our slider pictures.
And these are pretty neat because they allow us to pick a certain part of the color spectrum and narrow
down the color we want with these different shades.
And we also want to toggle the model by clicking on the cancellation.
So the last thing we'll do is add an unclick to our cancelbot which will reference our close model function.
So now we can show our color picker motile by clicking on the plus one and hide it by clicking on the
cancelbot.