Now when we click on the color picker mode or we want to be able to choose a color and then hit save
colors to create a new option within our color panel or the colors of our app.
So within a color panel component will bring in the segment component.
We're going to use this to wrap both of our labels and slighter pickers for primary color and secondary
color within our modal content area.
And on each of these segments we'll set a proper inverted so you can see the text of the label.
And then within our state we'll add a couple of properties one called primary and said to a string and
one of secondary.
So we want to use an onchange handler or both of the slider picker's and our first on change will be
set equal to a function handle change primary and the second or reference Hindle change secondary.
So first create Hindol change primary and sort of passing through an event we have access to the color
itself.
So we have this color object and it has a hex property on it.
We can get the hex code of the color that we selected with the primary color picker and we can modify
handle change primary to it'll change secondary to use the hex property of color to update the secondary
color and state as well.
Once we save that we will open our reactive tools we'll go to our caller panel component.
And when we pull up the state and we select a color for primary and secondary we can see that they're
updated in our seat object but the slider isn't moving to the part of the picture that we're selecting.
This is because we're not passing the values from primary and secondary and state back down to our slider
picker components.
So we need to make both of our slider picker's control components bypassing primary and secondary down
to the color prop on our respective slider pickers.
So now when we do that save our file and try updating the colors in our state again we bring up the
color panel open the model.
We can now change the area of the slider that we're selecting and the hex code that's attached to the
primary and secondary values and state.
We could also set primary and secondary to initial value since we're making these controlled components
and display by default a certain part of the slider picker for example the green and purple colors like
we have selected here and upon saving our colors by clicking on the colors.
But we want to create a color property for our currently authenticated user which will contain an array
of unique IDs and on them will be information about the colors that we chose.
The primary color with its corresponding hex code and the secondary color with that tax code.
So Koehler's will be a new property on our user object and our users collection
and to implement this will head back to our color panel
and go and on click to our saved colors by referencing a Hindol save colour's function which will create
so handles colors will first have a little bit of validation to make sure that we have values for both
the primary color and the secondary color and state will say if this does it are primary and this not
state DOT secondary and to set up this validation will remove the colors the tax codes that were previously
set for primary and secondary.
And if we have values for both primary and secondary will execute a function called Saved colors
and we can pass the primary value and secondary value
to safe colors.
No call them primary and secondary and we want to reach out to firebase and in particular we want to
use the user's ref you select a particular user will need to import firebase
then using the users or
we want to add a child
with the current user ID.
We need to have a user property in state referencing this not perhaps a current user and then pass our
current user data down.
To our caller Paymah
will do that and after chance
and once again will provide a key and will provide a somewhat unique identifier with current user name.
You'll notice that we are to use current user id for the side panel.
However we're sharing the same key value for a panel in messages so we'll change the key value to current
channel that name for the metal panel we want each of our components to have a different key value.
So we don't have any problems with passing down props or with rendering each of the components.
Now we can reference the caller's property for a user or push a unique identifier onto this new property
and we'll use the update method to push an object with both the primary and secondary colors which we're
getting from the parameters of safe colors and then again and then statement we're going to log colors
added.
If that's successful we're going to close the model and then catch any errors.
With catch Erl just use a console air.
Now as we say that and test out saving our first set of colors will open the modal and pick a couple
of colors.
A couple of particular shades of a given color will hit safe colors and looks like we're getting an
error we're trying to provide a path of object objects flash colors within our saved colors function.
So this needs to be the start state or user id slash colors
themselves try this again.
Pick another set of colors
then we'll hit say
we take a look at our log.
We see that the colors were added or motile was closed and now we're currently authenticated user.
We have a code property with a unique ID and the colors that we chose saved as keys primary and secondary.