Now we want to display the sets of colors that a user has picked and saved using the color picker model
and our color panel
to do that will first add a component that amount to set up a listener role check to see if we have
a value for our user property in St. will create an add listener function.
In fact all executed with the user id value will create this function which takes the user id or will
first create a variable called user colors.
So this equal to an empty array will take the user Xref selects a child which will reference the user
id slash colors and get everything on the caller's property.
Then we'll add an event of child added and then the snap callback will collect all of the user colors
that a given user has selected and put them onto the beginning of the array using the upshift method
and pass the Snap's value.
So if we log collected into our user colors array we see we only have one set of colors so far in that
array.
But this is the first step to displaying them.
Next thing we need to do is set state will set a user colour's property and state to update user colors
from an empty array to the colors that we collect with our child added event.
Then we can render or pull off user colors from St. and we'll create a function display user colors
and pass user colors array to it displays or colors will take the colors a riddle first check to see
that the length is greater than zero.
To see that we have colors.
And our map over the array are for each color we're going to display it in a fragment.
We're going to pull off the index of the color we're iterating over and set it as the key on the fragment
or first add a divider component then do the classic color container within that.
Now the div the classic color square
and within that class of color overlay
this color square div will have a background style set to colored up primary the primary color that
we've set for a given pair of colors and color overlay.
We have a background set to color dot secondary.
So now we want to style a kind of custom icon to display both of our colors within after DSS will create
a section for color panel that Jesus will begin with the color container and this will have a position
relative in overflow.
Hidden a weight of 35 pixels a border radius of three pixels around it a bit.
Then we'll have a color Square class with it with 35 pixels a height of 35 pixels then four color overlay.
We'll have a width of 85 pixels a height of 35 pixels and transform set to rotate 225 degrees these
styles that we applied to each of the classes will allow us to create a kind of icon a square icon that's
rounded and includes both of the colors as triangles adjacent to one another.
So it's clear that we want to update the colors with the colors displayed in this icon Ladden on quick
to the color container div and we want to execute an action called set colors which will create
and will put this on multiple lines.
I mean line arrow function so that we can pass through the arguments colored primary and colored secondary.
So you want to set these colors on global state.
So create within our types file a colors action types section.
We're going to have our first type of set colors that equal to a string of the same name.
Then in our index file of actions we'll create a color actions area where we will have our set colors
action.
It will take in the primary color and a secondary color for our app it's going to return a type of action
types that set colors and the payload object with the property and value of primary color and secondary
color.
Had or reducers file will create another reduce her function.
It's going to put its resulting values on this Koehler's property of state.
So I'll add that to combine reducers and once again our first step will be to create an initial color
state object which will have an initial value of primary color and secondary color as empty strings.
Our colors reduce her function we'll have a default value of states set to initial colors state and
the action
will switch based on the action type.
Our first case will be action types that set colors where we want to return an object where we're accepting
the value of primary color from the action.
In particular the action payload and the value for secondary color from our action payload.
And of course we need a default case in case none of our cases are met.
So back in color panel once again will need connect
and will need the action that we just made so that colors
then we'll wire everything together at the bottom.
Connect or wrap color panel
will set maps to Propst.
No.
And the structure are set.
Colors action will save everything.
And I'll add one more rule to our color container cursor pointer give a little pointer icon to let our
user know that these icons clickable and once we click on it will open our read ex-staff tools
and we should see on our state object this property with primary color and secondary color updated to
the values contained on the icon.
So now and after Jesus we need to use maps say to props
and we want to get primary color from state colors primary color and secondary color from dark colors
not secondary color.
Want to provide both these colors in different places in our app.
First the structure both those values from the props before we replace the background rules that we've
set using the style props for a number of components with primary color and secondary color.
We want to go back to our reducers folder and set the initial values for primary color and secondary
color and initial color state on does that the primary color to horsy greasy foresee hex code and the
secondary color to Tripoli.
So now this allows us to replace each of the background rules with either a secondary color or primary
color.
You've said that using the style props will set the grid component to a background of secondary color
and that will give it the default value of X could triple the or passed down primary color via props
to our side panel component.
And with unsigned panel you can see we have the background rule set for our menu component.
So the structure primary color from its props and replace background with primary color
will also pass it down to our user panel
that when we navigate to that component
we can change its background roll with primary color and make sure to restructure that from the props
object primary color from props we can directly separate the values of background.
Now I can save all those files
and when our page reloads for at we should see the initial colors that we've always had for our application
but when we click on the icon we should see immediately the colors change to the colors that the user
set on the icon.
We choose some new map colors.
For example say dark red
as well as some green hue say a darker green.
We click on Save we should see a new icon.
Both of those colors when we click on that the primary and secondary colors overlap should change globally.