Let's move on to building out our color panel and messages components will start with the color panel
which is on the left hand side of our side panel and within it will import a number of things from semantic
you react
or grab the sidebar menu divider and Button components.
So the main component will be a sidebar.
We want to use the as a prop to make it as the menu component that we imported will have additional
props.
I can set the labeled as was inverted vertical visible with a very thin and within the sidebar.
First have a divider to divide it from a button underneath with an icon of and have a size of small
and its color will be blue and say Will that take a look at it.
You can see a thin black color panel on the side with one blue button.
Now moving on to messages
Lamport from semantic UI
segment and comment and replace the starting to first of fragment.
We're going to group a number of custom components together within this fragment.
The first of which will be messages header component and we'll have our segment with a comment group
within it.
Which is where it will eventually put our messages and we'll give it a class name of messages this comment
group then underneath the segment we'll have another custom component of message form.
So first will create the file for our messages header within the messages folder.
So import react the top.
This will be a staple component go to the class name of messages header
will have its render and return and will first make sure to export it at the bottom.
Then at the top will bring in some components from automatic UI
or grab header segment and put an icon or begin into segment to group related content and we'll add
this clearing Propp.
Since we're going to be using a few floats within the segment.
This basically works as a clear fix when we float items to one side or another.
The header will have a fluid set to true will be as needed to be close to the left will give it a style
proc with margin bottom set to 0 and within our header here the text of channel and then to the right
hand side will have an icon with the name of star outline and the color for it will initially be black.
Will wrap the channel icon in a spam
and underneath the span tags will have a sub header for our header component which is where it will
show the number of users for a given channel.
For example two users are now oniony they will have another header which will be added to the right
so have an input and on that input give it a size of many icon will be search
the name will be search term and placeholder for the input will be search messages.
So this will be an input to search messages in a given channel and will just add a comment at the top
for our first hour of channel title and the second header will be channel search and put
the now back in messages we're going to import messages header from the same Polder
and now moving on to our message form create a new file for that and our messages folder
are again will import reac is again will be stateful.
The class message form extends react or component render return or export it
at the top will import from semantic UI.
Segment button and input
will begin with the segment again.
Give it a class name of message underscore underscore form within the segment of an input.
Here's where we'll be adding new messages to a given channel proper fluid.
The name of message style profit margin bottom set to zero point seven times a label which will include
a button which will have an icon of ADD or put the label to the left hand side.
The placeholder for the input will be.
Write your message then underneath the input will have a button.
Group will have a couple of buttons which will have proper icon and the width of two
so first button will have an orange color.
The content for it.
The text on the button will be ad reply and the label position will be left where the icon which will
be added.
Then the next button
in addition to being able to add or apply are going to have a button that will allow us to upload some
media with the color of green content of upload media or label position where the icon is right and
the icon is cloud.
Upload and once again with messages will import our component of message form from the same folder.
Well say that now we can see the basic structure of our messages component.
Now as you notice things are a bit stacked at the top.
We need to add a new section in our app that see as file first for our messages class with the height
of 440 pixels and overflow y of scroll.
This will be for our messages area where we can look at all the messages for a given channel then will
have a message form section with message.
Underscore under-perform the position of fixed and set to important.
The bottom for it will be 1 m margin left will be 320 pixels and important as well.
The left will be set to zero right one m and z index 200.
So it appears in front of everything else.
Say that.
Now I can see our messages area takes up much greater height and our message form takes up the majority
of the remaining with.