Your database will have messages collection for every new message that's added collection will be called
messages you will have as a child the channel ID that the message is written on and then that will have
a child of the message ID unique identifier of the message that's created in on this ID will have information
about the message namely the content of the message.
For example the text flow world the time stamp which is when the message was created as well as a user
object which will contain information about the user that created the message their ID their name and
their avatar
and we can add this example collection.
Take a look at what our messages collection might look like.
Rechanneled ID will have an array of messages that are added on the messages collection will have an
array of channel IDs for all the channels in our app.
We'll delete that and back to our messages component
and we'll first bring in firebase.
So import firebase from two levels of
nor create the messages for the ref to put messages on our messages collection.
So put that in state as firebase our database that but the string of messages and want to pass this
down to our message form via prop's so create a messages ref Propp and use the render function to restructure
our messages ref property from state
and pass that down.
And the reason for this is that we'll be creating our messages within the messages message form the
first within message form also create a state object which will hold the message.
It will have a property name of a message set to an empty string for now and will create an onchange
on the input to update that message property connected to handle change and this handle change functional
take the event so the state according to the name of the input and give it give the corresponding property
within state its value the value that is typed into the input and on the button on our ad reply button
we're going to add an on quick Hamburgh connected to a send message function.
We'll create send message and our first restructure from props are messages ref which we need to use
in order to create a message in our database.
We'll check to see if there's a message.
And only then will we send the message to will the structure from state or message property which holds
the content of our message.
And if there's a message we'll take the messages.
And actually before using that we'll set the state will set a voting property on state to true.
So add loading in our state initialize it to False take the message is.
You know we need to provide the channel ID as a child to specify which channel we're adding this message
to.
So to get that information we need to go back to our app file and pass it down to our messages component.
So we use map C to process to get our current channel from state channel that current channel
structure it and our prop's object or app and pass it down as a prompt to messages with the same name
Additionally it's important to know that when we're passing props in multiple components we need to
provide a unique identifier a key.
So to give our component the key word to be rendered properly will give it the current channel Id
say if there's a current channel we'll give our messages component the key of her channel that ID and
we'll do something similar for our side panel we'll give it a key value according to the current user
value we're passing in its unique identifier.
That's an important step in passing down props this way.
And now since we're passing down our current channel Propp to our messages component we can receive
it in our state object as Channel or the structure channel from state and render and pass that down
to message form as print channel.
Once again
then within its state
we can optionally receive it as channel from this stuff perhaps a channel.
Now we can do structure within and message channel from state and provide the child channel ID to get
the channel that we're on.
The idea of the channel we're on or push that onto the messages rather than set
a given message onto it.
Then how do we get that message.
Well we'll execute a function called create message to do the work for us.
Or create a message above our Send message function.
This will create an object to the variable message for us to have our content property
we get this from the message property in St..
And we also need a time stamp with the time stamp of when this message was created.
Because from the path firebase that database got server value that time stamp.
This is going to be received from firebase when our new message is added so we need to import firebase
from two levels up again in order to get that
then we have our user object you know contain three properties an ID.
So we need to also pass in our current user to our messages component the props
and then then messages receive that in our state as the user property and restructure it and pass it
down again to our message form as the Propp current user
will add user.
And our message form state as well.
This stuff prop's that current user
and then down within our user object will set the ID to this start state that user id the name will
be the start state user dot display name the Avatar does not state that user dot photo euro to get all
that user information about who created the message and we're going to return the message and pass it
to our set method then we're going to I don't know then statement
will set the stage.
Well that loading the false
will set the message to an empty string.
We also want to set and heir's property to an empty array so we want to track our errors any errors
that might take place in executing this.
So out there is property to state to catch the very end or will cancel error our error message if we
have one and we'll set the state or set the first loading property of state to false.
Once this is resolved that airs this state that errs and concatenate our air object onto it.
Otherwise.
Now that does handle the if condition.
If we do have a message if we don't have a message we're going to.
So the states are going to add an error to our heirs are they going to concatenate an object with a
message property of add a message
and on our input we can show this error.
We are the class name again with the structure from state within render
the arrows object the arrows array.
I should say I will use the some array method so if one of the elements in the arrows array includes
the text of message just like we supplied in our error message in our L's case.
If Erda message includes a text message we're going to show the error class.
Otherwise we'll show nothing.
Now if we save all the open our console
we had to react dev tools.
We go to our message form and take a look at our state.
Looks like we're saving our user and our channel so we have values for both of those
so we can get ad reply.
We get our air added to our ears re and state and we see our red outline now.
Try adding a message of hello world we see after adding it.
Our message was set to an empty string within state and we now have a messages collection in our database
with one message with the content of hello world as well as all of our user information and our time
stamp for when it was created.