We added our first message to our messages collection in our database where we didn't clear the text
in our input upon adding it.
So to clear that value whenever we add a new message or make our input and our messages form a controlled
input are passed on the value from our message property is being updated to our input component with
the value prop
or also disable or button upon adding a new message by setting the disabled prop to the loading value
of loading said to true it will disable our button while our messages message is being added.
So the structure loading from state as well.
So now when we clear our message property and state upon adding the message will also clear the text
that's within the input as well.
So now when we add our apply the text and the inputs queered our button is disabled for a split second.
Upon adding the reply.
And we have another new message within our database.