We've added some messages for our messages collection now we want to display those in or out for a given
channel within the messages component.
We set up our component dismount lifecycle method.
So when our component mounts or first check to see that we have a value in our global state for the
current channel and current user and we can get those guys from our state object as channel news or
we'll do structured those if there's a channel as well as the user will execute a listener's function
called add listeners and pass down the channel ID the current channel that we're on so we can add listeners
will have our channel ID parameter and as the name suggests we'll eventually have a number of listeners
within this function.
Our first listener will be the ad message listener will pass our channel ID that function as well.
With an ad message listener we're going to listen for any new messages added for a given channel for
first by creating an array called Loaded messages which will be empty.
Do not take our messages.
And select the child according to its channel ID and listen for a new child to be added.
And then we get this now.
And add the snap value to our loaded messages.
We are the push method and for now it will log or loaded messages or array within the console.
So if we take a look at our console on the first Hannele can see we have our two messages for that given
channel ID.
And once again we want to put these messages within state using said state.
The first will set messages the messages property to loaded messages and also have a property called
messages loading set to false to keep track of when our messages are loaded as well.
Add both of those to our state messages and messages.
Loading and it will be set to true by default only when we set up or add message listener messages loading
be changed to false.
Then will the structure messages then render.
Now iterate over it with a new function called display messages and pass our messages array to it.
The render or create display messages will take in that messages.
First check to see that the length of that array is greater than zero.
So we actually have some values for it and in that case we will iterate over the messages are using
the map method and print each message we will put the message via this message component which will
create in our messages folder so message that day as we will import re-act up at the top.
And this will be a seamless functional component because the message then will export message at the
bottom.
You know first import that in our messages file
and we're going to pass down a number of props to our newly created message component.
The first thing that we need to add is our key since we're iterating over this give it a unique identifier
message that time stamp will pass down the entire message object that we're getting as this message
prompt and also passed on the user the current user from our state object with this state user.
Then within message we'll build out our message component will grab the comment component from semantic
UI and this will be the parent component in our message
structure the message and user prop's or the proxy object.
The first thing within this comment I will include is the avatar of the user that created the message
will give it a source current or Avatar component a source of messages that user that Avatar and the
Avatar will have the content of the message.
The text of the message will put that within Commodore content.
But first we want to give it a classroom that's conditionally determined based on a function called
is own message which will take the message and user props will create this is own message outside of
our message component and then his own message will determine whether the ID of the user that's currently
authenticated is the same as the id of the user that created the message and give our comment if our
message compliant a special class.
In that case just to see visually that we wrote the comment or the person that's currently authenticated
wrote the comment.
So if those two ideas are the same we'll give it a class of message self otherwise no class within the
current content include the comment author the message author.
Make it as a tag and interpolate message that user name get the creator of the message and include some
comment meta data.
Namely we want to show the date or the time that it was created.
Once again will create another function which will call time from now it will take the message time
stamp when the message was created and convert it into a time from the current moment.
So we're going to use the date and time formatting library moment in order to format this time stamp
or to give us a period of time has passed since the comment was created.
So passen time stamp to the moment function and then we'll call the from now method on it.
Well that will give us the amount of time lapse since the comment was created.
Then oniony the time going to include the text of the message content the text itself.
Now we need to create this message self class within our applet CSSA file.
Create a separate section or a message component
in message cell consist of a border left of two pixels solid orange no padding left.
Of 8 pixels will just be a vertical line next to every count.
That's our message and you are two messages for our first Channel 4 channel are now appearing in our
messages section.