Before we touch on our messages Hetter we first need to disable or upload media on as a media file as
being uploaded.
We go down to within message form the upload media button.
We'll disable it when upload state is set to the text uploading so never disabling that when our files
being uploaded.
Now move on to our messages.
However we want to dynamically change the name and number of users for the channel that we're currently
on within the head or within messages will first create a function called display channel name.
It's going to take in the channel and with a turn every are going to if there is a channel within a
template literal display the channel name with channel name and prepend a hash mark in front of it.
Otherwise there's no channel will just show an empty string or pass down the channel name prop to messages
Hetter by executing display channel name bypassing in the channel that we have within our messages state.
Then within messages Hetter all these structures props within Rander to grab channel name and replace
our channel text with that value you can save both our files.
Now I can see the name of our channel up at the top in the header when we click on it.
Now we want to show the number of users that we have for a given channel.
The number of unique users that we have.
So we'll create a function that will execute within our ad message listener hold count unique users
and pass it the loaded messages that loaded messages array that were adding values to your account unique
users will take the messages or a
will create a variable called unique users.
And on this mess desir we're going to use the reduce method to an array method that allows us to get
an accumulated value for a certain type of operation.
So the first parameter to it will be the accumulator and then the value of the item that we're iterating
over the message and the initial value of our accumulator will be this empty array that we specify at
the very end of redos.
First we'll set up a conditional to check to see if the accumulator array includes the value message
that user doesn't name.
If it doesn't include a certain user's name then we'll add it to our accumulator with the push method
or push message that user name onto it.
So we'll have an array of names within this accumulated array and then we'll make sure to return it
at the end.
It's very important return the accumulator for the end of reduce.
Then we have our unique users array who create a variable called non-unique users the number of unique
users will again use a template literal will interpret the length of the unique users.
And then at the end add the text users so get the number of users unique users that we have and then
set the local state by creating a property name of some unique users give the variable the same name
of the property the same name as the variable that were creating initialized that to an empty string.
Then we can begin our under the structure name unique users and pass it to our messages header as a
prop
and like with our channel name will grab name unique users from a proxy object or place that fixed value
that we had with unique users.
Save our files and backstrap and underneath our name the name of our channel can see the number of unique
users who have created messages in a channel we can see for this Riak channel that we have incorrectly
one users and sort of one user so we can detect whether users the text users should be plural not within
our account unique users function by creating a variable called pleuro.
Will check our unique users right.
Its length.
See if its greater than 1 or if unique users that length is equal to zero.
In that case we want to add an s we want use to be plural or remove the ass and set up a turn every
We'll check to see if plural is true.
If so I hadn't asked otherwise for include an empty string.
For example if we have one user one unique user we're only going to show the text one user instead of
users plural.