Nelse the ability to search messages for a given channel where you can type into the search and put
get returned to us all the messages that match what we typed in so on our input and our messages had
her live and onchange and connected to a function.
Now the function that we were connected to will be within our messages component and so we want to update
the state here that this function will be called Hindol search change.
We will take the event from the Change event and at set the state set the property on state called search
term according to that either is typed in with event of target value we need to create a search term
within our messages state will also create a property called Search loading which will initially be
set to false.
They also want to track when this search operation is being performed with search loading.
So when were setting the state or setting the value of our search term that search loading to true
then we need to pass down the function to our messages header.
Or pass it as the prop Hindle search change
then within messages header will grab it from our prop's
and attach it to our onchange.
So now when we type into the input or updating the state the messages stay but now we need to filter
the messages that we have within our messages state to add a callback function when our search term
is updated upon calling said state will execute a function called handle search messages which will
do that filtering operation for us.
So create this function right underneath the handle search change.
The first thing we need to do is copy the message to the array that we have in state using the spread
operator will spread all the values of just RC dot messages and assign it to an array called channel
messages to make sure that we dont mutate the original messages or they will create a Redjacket using
the regexp constructor.
We do that first by providing a pattern which will set with dynamically with the search term value from
the start date search term and then will provide a flag.
And this will indicate that we want our red X to be applied globally and case insensitively so to the
entire string that we're matching with the Red X as well as making sure that the case of the text doesn't
matter or create a search results or they will take general messages use Reduce to go through the entire
channel messages re.
And we'll have our accumulator initially set to an empty array.
And each of the values that we iterate over will be called message
and to add new values to.
We'll check to see if message content got match we'll use the match method to apply a red X to the content
of the message.
If we have a match with our rejects on the content of the message we will push the entire message onto
our accumulator on to our array.
Now it's possible that our message might include an image instead of a content property so we need to
first check that a given message has the content property and if that's the case at the very end of
reduce we'll return the accumulator then once we have our search results we'll set the state or set
a search results property on state.
So create that
will make search results an empty array.
And now in a return we need to set up a conditional a ternary to check to see that we have a search
term we'll check to see if we have a search term.
If so we're going to use display messages and pass it the search results array.
Otherwise we'll execute display messages.
Just passing the entire messages or a
structure both search term and search results.
Are this ternary.
Now we can say both files and test this out in our search.
We type in the letter H and C we're matching all of the messages that contain letter H I can type in
high.
Now I only get the messages with the text high and if I type in a capital H we get the same matches.
So again this regexp is being applied is case insensitive and it's matching the entire content string
but we can't search for users we can't search for the messages that an individual user has created.
So to add that ability go back to your handle search messages function and add this or conditional to
apply our rejects to message user name or apply that to the name of the user that created a given message.
So if we save that now I can search for a user like Bethanie and get all that all that users messages
or Thomas can see we're getting all of their messaging messages including their image messages.
And one additional thing we can add just as a small UI feature is our search loading property from state.
If you recall we're setting search loading to true when this search operation is taking place.
Passed down search loading as a prop to messages header and receive it first by structuring it from
the proxy object then put it on our input component as this loading Propp.
So when that said to true we'll have this little loading icon be a nice indication of our loading our
search operation taking place.
So back within our handle search messages after setting the search results are all set search loading
the false and we'll do this after a period of maybe one second.
So use a set time out and pass a value of 1000 milliseconds to it.
So now when we type into our search we get this little learning animation on the right hand side
just a nice little indication to show our users what's taking place when they type into it.