Now it's great the structure for a direct message is component which will be underneath our channels
component that all allow users to send messages directly to other users.
Within side panel and component direct messages on their channels.
Create a file for it in the side panel folder.
Over the top will import react.
This will be a staple component of all those classic direct messages
will have its return and render well make sure to export it at the bottom.
That's where a default will import it within side panel.
Before we forget
and will be in the same folder
and our direct messages the structure of the component will look very similar to how we structured our
channels component import menu icon from semantic UI
and our main component will be menu menu with the class name of menu
and it will contain a menu item.
Once again with this span an icon within it with the name mail.
The text in all caps of direct messages include our curly braces and our coats with a space in between
to space it from our parentheses which will include the length of the number of channels that will have
and will designate that with this user's property within state.
Will the structure users then render the number of direct messages channels with users not link.
Then I don't eat the menu item include a comment or tell us later that's where it will iterate over
the users that will be able to send direct messages to and back channels.
You'll notice that we had a style prop on the menu setting Padam padding bottom to two homes or replace
that with the class name of menu and within after CSSA will create that Menu class
so this menu class will be within our side panel.
No just give it a roll where we set padding bottom to two m's.
Now we have the basic structure for our Direct Messages component.