Now it's display the users that we can send direct messages to and our direct messages component
to direct messages.
The first thing we need here is the current user data that you'll get from the parent component the
side panels or pass current user down as a prompt to direct messages.
Once we have the current user data we'll put it in our state as the user property
when our component mounts we're going to check to see that we have some user data that it's NOT KNOW.
If so we'll call a function called add listeners and pass the user id to it to create this add listeners
function which takes the current user ID and is going to collect all of the users that aren't currently
authorized authenticated user or first import firebase from firebase.
Now the users are up to date.
First create an empty array called Loaded users will take the user's wrath and most incur any new children
that are added and within the snap callback
will check to see that the current user ID is not equal to snapshot.
This is because we don't want to include within our loaded users or ourselves the currently authenticated
user or create a user variable be equal to the value of this snap.
Well I had a couple of properties the first being the id property to be equal to snapshot key and the
status of the user which will initially be set to offline then will take each of these user objects
push it onto the loaded user's array.
Then put it within local state said state onto the user's property.
Then underneath our users Raffl this connected router.
This is a wrap which will give us information about the user's status.
As to whether they are connected or not.
And all users connected with which gives us some better information about each user in our app.
To listen for a change in the value.
So if there's a value change for a given user with the connected we're going to update a new collection
that we'll create in our database called presence and presence will consist of an array of user IDs.
And a value of true.
So this Namen value pair that users you you ID in there and the value true will be set.
Only if the user is online to indicate their presence within the app or this is how we'll track the
users online status as well as their off line status.
So if it's now equals true it there is a value change for a given user on the connected drop first ad
the present practice date referencing firebase the database ref with the string of preference.
We're going to take the presence for
no added child to it with the current user you ID will call this value graph and set it to true.
Set the value of that to true.
And I'll also add this disconnect method.
In the case that if our user disconnects from the app will remove it with the Remove method and catch
any errors in the process.
So now that we're tracking the users online status with the presence raw underneath we'll take it and
listen for the child added event.
So if there is a new child added a new user is added to our presence or as the value of true and you
I.D. is not equal to snapshot.
Once again are you going to add a status to the user.
And we do that with a function of first copy this and paste it in right underneath and listen for the
child removed event.
You want to listen for when a child is added and a child is removed to the presence rack and or create
or add status to user function.
This will take a user ID and a connected value which by default would be set to true
will create a variable called updated users.
I will go through the users array with the reduce method which has an accumulator and iterate over each
user value.
And I'll check to see if the user ID is equal to user ID.
As well as if a connected value connected is passed a value of true.
If so going to put the status of the user as online if not would make them online then we'll concatenate
each user back onto the accumulator and then set the date or set the users array with the updated users
array.
Then with them the child added again this conditional that we set up where when a child is added to
the presenter will execute as services or and passed the snapped key.
And when a child is removed we'll set the connected argument to false indicating that our users are
not connected and that we should give them a status of off line.
And finally within our menu will iterate over the users map over them and all the user data will be
within a menu item component.
The key will be user got you I.D. serpent Arncliffe or chronologies console log the user data set the
style of the menu item its opacity to 0.7 and the font size to a taluk
and within the menu item will have an icon
the name of circle and the circle will show the status of the user whether they're online or offline
with a color or the color will execute this function is user online will run its user online and if
it returns true will give the iconic color green.
Otherwise a color of red I indicate that there are online.
So is yours or online will take the user will check the user status to see if it's the text online.
If it's true once again or have a color of green then underneath the icon will just interpolate the
user name with user name.
Now if we head back to our app and we refresh our direct messages we should see another use in our app
that's not ourselves.
Or we can send direct messages to and on our present track.
We should see one value of true which is us the currently authenticated user.