When I click on a user to send a direct message to we want to put the channel information the global
stage just like we did for channels component but for the time being we're just logging the data for
the user that we clicked on to change or cancel logging the user data and change that with a call to
his change channel function which takes the user data.
So create change channel.
It takes a user
and we first need to get the channel ID which will store in a variable and will be the return value
of a function that will create called Get Channel ID which takes the user id
so in get channel ID
are going to compare the user ID that we clicked on with the current user id so make the current user
id its own variable check to see if they used that we clicked on ID is less than the authenticated users
ID.
If so we use template literals to interpret the user id and forward slash.
And then the current user ID to create the path of the channel.
Otherwise we put the current user ID first and then the user ID that we clicked on.
So this allows us to make a unique channel identifier for every direct messages channel.
Now we have a channel ID will make this channel data object in our change channel function consists
of an ID equal to channel ID a name equal to user name.
And then we will take this channel data and pass it to our current channel action which we have on our
props or at least we will put on our props first by importing the connect function from reactor's docs
and then importing that current channel from our actions folder
then at the bottom will combine both of them and connect
that NULL to map state to props and then we'll restructure set corrent channel from Mount dispatch to
prop's.
So now we have that current channel on our prop's you also want to execute another action.
Want to put in global state that this is a private channel with the actions that private channel and
passing the value of true within types will create a new channel action type called said private channel
to the actions index file of the new channel action with the same name but in camel case.
So take a boolean.
Joe Cole is private channel to return an object with the type of action from action types Scott said
private channel and the payload would be an object just a property is private channel since the property
name and value are the same.
Then in our reducers folder an index will add a property to initial channel state the initial channel
state object is private channel set to false by default.
Why add a new case for action types.
That said private channel and will in the return spread the state and said Is private channel property
to action up haloed that is private channel
the back and direct messages can use this new action or important
bringing in at the bottom
will save all of our files and test this out.
Go to our redux dev tools and will try clicking on one of our direct messages channels.
We take a look at our channel property we see our new some property is private channel set.
Initially the false
click on our one direct message channel can see that we called Set private channel as well as current
channel.
You see our user at the top of the messages Hetter and that given current channel now the idea is set
this very long path with BIRTON the user IDs
and are also setting is private channel to true.