One real quick only direct message is channel or a setting is private channel to true within our global
state who look on a public channel.
We're not changing that back to false.
They want to designate that a public channel that we click on is not a private channel and our global
state.
So head to our channels component
and within changed channel will execute that private channel pass and a value falls to it.
And we'll bring in the private channel from our actions folder and the structure from map dispatched
to props and connect will save our channels component
and first click on a direct messages channel where he said is private channel the true then a public
channel.
Now we're setting it back to force the next thing we'll do is head back to apologise or we'll use maps
to props to get the current value of his private channel.
We need to know whether a given channel that we're in is private and a number of places within our messages
component.
So grab that value from apps it's a prop's pass it down to our app component or the structure from the
prop's object and pass it down again using props to our messages component where it will receive the
messages state their value as the property private channel
in the first place will use it is within our display channel name function.
We want to display private channels differently than public channels within the body.
This function now will check to see or past the channel and then if so we use a template literal to
set up a turnaround.
Or will check to see if it's a private channel.
If so prefix the channel name within at symbol.
Otherwise a hash mark for a public channel will add the channel name with channel name.
Otherwise if it's not a channel we'll just return an empty string then grab the private channel value
from say and pass down that value with props once again to our messages are important.
We want to use this to conditionally show our star icon star icon will soon be a button which will use
to star in On-Star channels.
Set up a conditional surrounding it to check if it's not a private channel.
If it is a public channel only then will we show the star icon.
Will users be able to soon star a given channel then will pass down as private channel with profs once
again to our message form component and here we'll use that value to determine the file path where we're
uploading a given file.
So instead of the file popping chat slash public we'll interpolate interpellation execute a function
a new function called Get path which will determine which path we should use based on whether the channel
that we're in is private or public.
So then get path if it's a private channel we're going to return a custom path based on the channel
Id return once again using template literals chat slash private and then slash or or dash channel ID
from the state object.
Otherwise the public channel will just return chat slash public and back within our messages component
will create a new property called private messages.
We're going to create a new raft a new raft which will reference a new collection within our database
called private messages.
This is where all of our private messages from private channels will be stored
and will create a function within the messages component called get messages.
So this will be important in a couple of cases returning which rap we should use when sending a message
will restructure a few values from stay within this function.
Messages are private messages and private channel will be quite simple.
If it's a private channel that we're in we're going to use the private messages.
Otherwise the message is rock
so we'll use this in our ad message listener were previously using just the messages from say so create
a variable called ref or will execute messages ref and change that with messages.
Then we'll pass that down to our message form be approx
And we'll also use it within the upload file function
and this ref variable Well now references up Propst I get messages ref were well executed and here within
send message will also pluck off from our prop's object that messages ref and use it here in sending
off our message.
So now so so sending both a text message as well as an image message on our direct messages channel
for one user that we have
that looks like we can send text content and if we try getting an image file that sends a message
looks like that successful too.
So our get messages right and all of the changes that we made in our configuration seem to be working
properly.
We head back to our database.
You see our private messages collection or if we drill down we can see two messages within our 1 channel
a content a message with text content and one with image content.
If we had to our storage area and click on the chat folder then we see this private folder with the
channel ID
if we drill into that we can see the one image file that we added.