Now just like in our channels component we're giving an active class to the active channel that we've
selected.
We want to do the same with our direct messages so we can see which direct messages channel that we're
on.
To do so within our direct messages state we'll have an active channel property
and then within change channel We'll update that property depending on the channel that we're changing
to that we're clicking on by calling that active channel passing in the User ID and will create that
active channel which takes the user id and sets the state sets the active channel property that we just
created with the user id
then will from our state object the structure active channel from render and add an active prop to a
menu item that we are iterating over or we'll compare the user id with the active channel value and
state will say that
if we click on indirect direct messages channel.
Now we see a visual indication in our side panel of which direct messages channel that were on.