Let's create a modal when we click on change Avatar we give our users the ability to change their avatar
as they like in our user panel component on the spam or the text change avatar or connect an open modal
function and will bring in the mobile component from semantic UI and the state will set the modal property
to False and open modal will set the modal property and state to true or copy this function and for
function called Close modal we use that to set modal to false
structure modal from state and render.
And at the bottom before the closing tag of our great column are going to include our change user Avatar
motile once again will create a model component that some basic styling.
The Open will be linked to the modal value in state non-closed will be linked to the close model function
or model will have a header.
The text change avatar
as well as the content
includes an input so grab the input component from semantic UI
the input will have a proper fluid type of file a label of new avatar The change their avatar to a new
image file the name of preview image
underneath is input will have a grid component which will have the proper centered and stackable will
be two columns within this grid.
These columns can stack one on top of another will first include a grid row which will also have the
proper centered and then a grid column within it.
The class name of UI center aligned grid is semantic.
You will UI class
within this column will have the image preview and the next column will have the cropped image preview
to allow users to crop their avatar image as they like.
I need the modal content will have some buttons in modal actions.
Bring in the button component
and this first button
of the color green will be inverted.
Then the button tags of an icon the name of save the text of change Avatar will copy this button paste
it into more times.
Underneath
the next button will have icon of the name of image in the text preview and the last button will have
a color red.
The name of remove the icon in the text of cancell and on the cancel button one on click connected to
close modal function to close are modal.
Let's test this out see if we can toggle our change Avatar modal has had to change avatar on the drop
down b c are modal and we can close it with the cancel button.