Next we want to be able to click on our change Avatar option choose a file and have a preview displayed
underneath the file input in order for us to crop.
So back in user panel
on the input we'll add an onchange to put the file that we select within state reference a handle change
function
and handle change will take an event where once again we'll have a file variable that will reference
the first file.
The files are a from event target.
And here we're going to use the file reader API in order to.
Once we check to make sure that we have a file within our how variable we're going to use the reader
and this read as a data you are all method to read the file or then our RIDO will listen for the Load
event and then the callback that we're going to set the preview image property within state to reader
dot result.
So create a preview image add that to an empty string in St..
And now we want to bring in a tool called Avatar editor from re-act Avatar editor
and this is what you use to crop the image.
The preview image that we now have access to.
So all these structure preview image from state and then within the first grade column will take the
preview image.
And if we have a preview image we're going to show the Avatar editor component where it accepts an image
Propp which will set equal to preview image.
Give it a weight of 120 pixels and the height of the same and a border of 50 pixels and we can scale
the image with the value of 1.2 to make it zoomed in a bit more.
Now once we save that and we select Change Avatar we choose a file.
Now we can see our avatar editor.
So now what selected within this box is what we use to crop our image and then we'll click on the preview
button in order to perform the cropping.
So and in unclick to our preview button that they're equal to handle crop image
so create this new function.
To crop our preview image we need to add a ref to our avatar editor component.
So had this ref Propp and on the ref we want to create an inline function.
We passed this value of node and assign it to
Avatar editor
So Avatar editor is now in our class we can reference it with this avatar Ed. We'll first check to see
that we have this reference then on this ref we can execute the method.
Get image scaled to canvas.
This will do the cropping or image and we want to convert this to an image blob so we use the method
to blob within that callback we get access to the return blob.
We want to create an image Israel by taking the create object your own method and passing in the BLOB.
And we want to set state you want to put the image that we're creating on this cropped image property
and pass the blob to its own property and state where the cropped image property will allow us to see
another preview of the image that we've selected with the Avatar editor component and the blob will
be necessary for sending the image file over to firebase storage.
So the structure cropped image from state within render and then within our second grade column we're
going to first check to see if we have a value for a cropped image in state.
If so we're going to render an image component whose style property will be set to margin equal to point
five AMS auto with 100 pixels a high of 100 pixels a source set to cropped image.
Then we'll head down to our change Avatar button we'll set up a condition where we'll only show this
one if we have a cropped image
and once we save that file
we can test this out.
We're going to change avatar.
We'll choose a file
we'll see our preview
and once we click on the preview button we can see the cropped image with the selection that we chose.
We can change that selection and hit preview again if we like to get a different crop.
And then in the next section we'll set up the functionality for our change Avatar button in order to
persist the changes that we made with our image.