We're now cropping the preview image that we have for our avatar now we want to enable the functionality
for change Avatar button to actually change the image that's associated with a given user.
So I hadn't unclick to our change our carbon which reference a new function called upload cropped image.
So as the name suggests it will upload the image of a user's cropped to firebase storage
so create this function.
And in order to upload her image will need to reference our storage and firebase with a storage rackin
state
which I'll use firebase of storage and NMT RATH
So we'll use this storage to and above it we can structure it from state to the path to it is just storage
raw
and we want to put a child on it.
And we'll use some template literals to reference Avatar's flash user dash and then we'll interpret
the current user ID and instead of getting the current user information from prop's we're going to create
a user app which is going to reference 5 based on our current user.
And this is an alternate way to get the current users de-value we can restructure user from state and
get their ID with user after UAD we use the put method to put our image in firebase storage.
We want to grab the blog from state and also put some associated metadata with it.
So create a meta data object and state which will have a content type property with the file type image
flash JPEG with this meta data object.
We're going to be uploading all of our images as JPEG files were added then after executing put.
Are we going to get a snap back after uploading or image and on the property we're going to execute
the get download euro method.
We'll add it then since this is a promise or we'll get the download Eurail from firebase storage and
we want to set the property in state called uploaded cropped image with the download euro.
It will create uploaded cropped image within our state
and within the callback we're setting this property romantical a function called Change Avatar.
So at this point we've done the first part.
We've uploaded an image to firebase storage as an image blob and then change avatar.
We're going to first take this user that we have and call the up to profile method on its in order to
update our users photo euro property
and we'll update it with the download bureau that's within this art center uploaded cropped image.
Why then since this is a promise or will log
go to your all updated
and we'll close the model and we'll catch any errors with catch.
And in addition to updating a user's profile with the user we want to update their associated data on
our users RAF in our firebase database or create a user's property referencing firebase database and
the users collection
will set a child on the user to get the logged in user.
When I use this that's data you ID you want to update their information and specifically the Avatar
property with this does data uploaded cropped image and then if that returned successfully
will get a logo user Avatar updated.
And once again we'll catch any errors.
We'll save all of our files.
Also make sure to restructure the metadata property state within upload cropped image.
If you haven't already
will try going through the entire process of changing our avatar will select Change Avatar will choose
a new image file
will select the crop that we want and we'll hit preview and finally will click on change avatar and
you can see immediately within our avatar image and our user panel that the Avatar was changed.
We see both of our logs user Avatar updated 40 updated.
If we take a look at the data we're currently authenticated using our database we should see that the
Avatar euro now references firebase storage.
If we take a look at our storage we should see a new folder of avatars we click on that we see user
dash and then some cryptic string and there we should find the image that we uploaded our cropped image.
You can see its name size the type of image size JPEG when it was created.
And now if we try adding a new message to one of our channels we can see our new avatar next to our
message.