When other users are typing in the same challenge that we're currently in it be nice to see an animation
at the very bottom of the given channel in order to see that they're preparing a message.
Other users are preparing a message so head to our message form component and we'll begin by adding
an on key down handler to our message and put this whole reference a new function called handle key
down.
So create or handle key don't function say underneath handle change handle key down will be a bit different
it won't take an event but it will first check to see if we have some value stored in our message property
of state.
We can structure that from state.
Then the function then will access a typing Raf's so create a new property within state called typing.
The sole reference.
A new collection in our database we haven't used before with the name of typing assigned to it.
We can grab that from state as well.
It'll have a child set equal to the channel ID that we're currently in.
And another child with the User ID would make sure that the structure that is well from state and nested
within these two children are going to set a value of user data display name so the users name if they're
currently typing in a given channel.
Otherwise if we don't have a message
we're going to remove that value that we just said on the typing Ralph
So to test this out or type into a given channel.
Take a look at our database.
We should see a new typing collection with the channel ID within that the user id and the name of the
user.
And once we remove everything from the message input we remove all the text we should see that typing
collection removed entirely.
And when we're sending a message of course the current user is no longer typing.
So within then once we successfully sent off a message we want to remove the typing RAF that references
the current user
and the structure user from state within send a message as well as the typing route.
When we change the channel we want to remove the typing ref as well for a given user.
So then change channel and our channels component will recognize the typing raw from state passen the
channel ID to the first child user ID to the second child and use the Remove method again and within
channels of course we need to first create the typing graph.
So if we change a channel or obviously no longer typing in the channel we were previously in.
So thats why its being removed now to test both of these cases out first.
Type into our input we see our typing collection we send a message.
We see that that is removed for our current user we type in again we see the added we switch to a different
channel.
We see that the entire collection is removed.
So this is the approach that we'll use to determine if other users are typing in the same channel that
we're currently in.