Now move on to our Taiping animation for either of the users that are currently typing in a given channel
we'll create a typing component within our messages folder or first or import react.
This will be a seamless functional component.
Or we'll have a typing do with the class of typing which will contain three divs with the class of typing
underscore underscore dot at the end will export our typing component and then at the bottom of that
CSSA create a new area or a typing component or first we'll have a user typing class or font style or
be set to a taluk what we will be bold and it'll have a margin right of three pixels.
So this will be the text NextEra animation the typing class will have with five M's a height of Tooms
a position of relative padding of 10 pixels margin marked five pixels of background.
But the tax code U-6 E-6 E6 a border radius of 20 pixels
and our typing got class.
We floated to the left will have a width of eight pixels a height of 8 pixels a margin of zero and four
pixels in the background color of 8.
The eight see nine one a border radius of 50 percent and opacity of zero and all create an animation
with the name loading Faid will be 1 seconds and will be an infinite animation.
We're going to select the first typing class with the aunt and child selector will select the first
typing up by passing that one will have an animation delay of zero.
The second typing class will have a delay of two seconds and the third delay of point four seconds.
So the animation for each dot will be slightly offset to create or animation that keyframes with the
name of loading fade at zero percent the opacity of the animation will be zero.
That's 50 percent will have opacity of zero point eight and at 100 percent it will go back to zero.
So now in our messages component we'll make sure to import our typing components from outside typing.
And then to display it just to preview this will go within our common group or will create a span of
the class team of user underscore underscore typing.
And just as some sample text will say Douglass's typing include the typing component to the right hand
side and or at both the span and the typing component with a div with a style prompt with the style
rules display at the flex line item set to center and this will center our span and our typing components.
Along the y axis
so now you can see the text and our typing animation.
So this is what will be shown for any user that's typing within the same channel that we're currently
in.