We've created our typing component.
Now we want to display this component for every user that's typing within the same channel that are
currently authenticated user in so out and execute a new listener function and add listeners and our
messages component called add typing listeners will accept the channel ID.
And within this function or first create an array called Taiping users to collect all the users typing
within a given channel based on its ID.
So on the state object we'll add our typing graph referencing firebase to our database and ref with
the string of typing will take this not state that typing graph will pass channel ID as a child to it
and listen for the child at an event and within unsnap or first check to see if a snapshot key is not
equal to this start state that user ID and were performing this check to make sure that were not collecting
the currently authenticated user within this typing users.
We use the concat method to concatenate an object on the end of the array with an ID set to snapped
key
and a name property set the snapshot value.
So we're collecting the user's ID and their name and we're redesigning the typing user's array and we'll
set state will set our typing users array within state.
So we need to create this new property initially set to an empty array
and also have an addition to our child added event.
We're going to have
our child removed event with the same child channel ID on our typing.
And within a snap callback we're going to take the typing users are they going to use the find index
method which will iterate over every user element we want to compare the user id property with snapshot
key and if there is none index value that's positive.
If an index can't be found We're going to use the filter method.
Or will iterate once again over the Taiping uses array and will make sure that none of the Ids within
each of these elements is equal to Samter key or reassign the typing user's array once again and set
the state.
Now that we're listening for children being added or removed from our typing ref we're going to once
again use the connected graph to determine whether a user is online or not and that all reference firebase
to database Aref the text in post-blast connected
will take the connected from say listen for a value change and within the snap callback will first check
to see if sample values equal to true.
Then we'll take the Taiping graph will take a child on it of the channel ID a child with the current
users user ID will add the on disconnect method.
And to also add remove.
So when are currently authenticated user logs out there child value on the typing half will be removed.
Now we'll head down to render
and first of all these structure Taiping users from St. and then head down to our div we were out where
we were outputting the span of the text that we provided as well as our typing component and replace
that with a call to a new function called display typing users where we'll pass the typing users or
a few.
We want to iterate over all of the elements in this typing user's array and state.
We first want to check to make sure the length of that array is greater than zero.
If so we'll map over it with the map method and we'll paste in the market that we copied
or will change.
First of all the style prop to include a margin bottom rule 0.2 EMS
and give it a key prop said to use or not ID or place the hardcoded username with user data name.
We'll save our changes and once again all deploy my app with the now Selye and once it's deployed are
paste in the deployed euro to different tab
and bring this over to the side we'll sign in with a different user than the one currently authenticated
in our dev server.
We'll make sure when I'm on the same channel or react you can see now we have our typing animations
saying that Thomas is typing and there are other user types in Thomas's page.
You can see that Douglas is typing.
We can remove this animation if we clear our message input and if we start typing again.
And see it again if we post or message typing animation goes away.
And the same for other user.
We switch back to another channel.
You'll see that we only see that typing animation when our users are on the same channel.
So now we've got our functionality to display when other users in the same channel are typing.