We're now able to add messages to a channel and see them displayed almost instantly within our messages
section you can switch to another channel and keep our messages within their respective channels.
But now let's move on to our upload media button.
We want users to be able to add images to their channels and we'll do that with an in our message form
component.
We want to create a modal property set initially because we'll be using a model just like we did with
our ad channel motile more channels component.
So we'll create a function called Open modal which will set the modal property in state to true to make
it visible or modal or adding a new media file and will connect this function to an on click handler
on or upload media button
into this player mode or put it within a custom component called File motile
and we want to pass down to our file modal first are modal value and state passes a modal prog.
So the structure that from stay within Rander class modal down to file modal as well as a close modal
function as a proper close model.
We can copy and paste our open modal function and modify it.
Be close model or we'll set the modal property of state within message form to pause to hide or modal
pass it down.
Or create a new file in our messages folder file modal
import reacts at the top.
This would be a staple component
will have its render and return
export file modal at the end.
You want to grab from semantic UI modal input button and icon
start with our modal component and on it will have the basic prop and basic styling.
The visibility would be talkable the open prop or pass the modal prop that we're getting from our parent
component down to it as well as close model or pass model to open and Antos of a value of close model
function.
And we'll have a header within our model that takes up select an image file
and we'll have a content section which will include the input where users can select a file will have
the proper fluid level of the file types that they need to include or have the label file types.
Jay pegan TNG name of it the name of this input will be file type will be file and underneath the modal
content include some buttons within a modal action section for the first button will have a color green
be inverted.
We can see the text
within the button tags will have an icon name so to checkmark in the text of send
to send our selected file or copy that button pasted in underneath.
Give it a color of red name.
Remove the text of cancel to cancel sending the given file and give it an on click of close modal
to be able to cancel sending a given file.
The back of our message form you need to import all modal up at the top.
From that sosh file modal
can save both those files.
If we click on upload media we can see our file model or we can choose a file we can hit cancel to close
the modal.