We want users in our app to click on upload media to choose an image file hit send and see their image
file added to their channel that they're currently on.
The first step to doing that within five modal is to create a state object with a file property set
initially to know Ladden onchange handler to our file input connected to a function called add file
to be able to add the file that a user selected to state this advice functional taken event and the
path to access that file will be event that target files.
This will be an array or select the first element with the index of 0 and for now let's log that value.
We're back in our app or click on upload media will choose an image file.
We can see that image file in our console we can see information about it such as its name its size
its type a bunch of information.
But instead of logging it we want this to be added to our file modal state.
We'll check to see if there is a value for this file variable.
We're going to set the state in particular the file property with the value in that variable.
Then on our Send button on click handler connected to this send file function that will create.
So whenever we hit send we execute send file and within it we'll restructure the file from state and
once again we'll check to make sure the file property and state is an empty and then one credit check
using this is authorized function that takes the file name to see if the file type or the file that
the user is trying to upload is authorized to perform this check at an authorized property than our
state object which will include an array of file types that we will allow allow file types of images.
So I bag and image slash PNB
with or is authorized function.
It takes the file name I'm going to use that authorizer A were just created or used the includes array
method to check to see if our file that's been uploaded includes that file type.
But in order to assist in determining that file type we'll import a tool called mime from the package
MIME types.
So MIME type or mime will perform a lookup for us using Outlook.
Look up the content type of the file based on its filename this I will check to see if the file that's
been attempted to be uploaded is of an authorized type and if it is if that returns TRUE going to create
this metadata object the content type property once again will use MIME to look up passen the file name
in order to put the content type of the file is trying to be uploaded on this meta data object.
And we want to pass it to a function called upload file which will take the file itself as well as this
metadata object upload file function as one that will create in our message form are created in the
parent component.
Upload file take file and metadata.
And for now we'll just lock both of those files to see that this function works.
And now we need to pass the function down to file modal to be used
passes down as the proper upload file
back and file model will be structure our products within sandpile grab the upload file function there
can execute it and we want to close our modal to also grab that from prop's upon uploading the file.
Then we want to clear the file went to where the file and state will create a function called Clear
file.
Ill just call that state and set the file property to No
now and save everything and give this a shot
open or cancel and then go to our re-act up towards
had to arc while motile we see RC With file an authorized we'll try selecting an image file
like the one I have in my desktop.
Looks like the file property was updated in state with this file object.
And if we click on send the modal property set to false.
The models are moved and we see in our console both the file that we uploaded and all of its data is
being logged from our upload file function as well as the meta data object.
And if we try clicking the send button without any image file selected we see we don't get anything
off to the console.