To upload an image to firebase and to post that image as a message we'll head back to our upload file
function within message form or we'll first create a path to upload variable which reference the channel
ID within state and or create a ref variable which will reference our messages ref from prop's then
will create this file path variable which will use template literals in the beginning and the path will
be a chat slash public.
Then after the next slash we use a function called do you ID before you ID Sastry before to create a
random string.
So we'll interpret that and call you you IDB for and end the path with that jpeg.
Then we're going to set state.
We want to set the upload state to the string uploading as our files being uploaded as well as the upload
task property as first create.
Both of these properties within state upload state will be set to an empty string initially an upload
task will be set to No.
We'll also have a storage rack and this is the way that we'll reach out to firebase in order to store
image.
This all references sors module.
And we'll just have an empty wrapper for now.
So for upload task we're going to reference our store for
and put a new child onto it.
And the child will be the file path variable that we created and we're going to put both the file and
metadata that we're getting within the function on that child.
So this is what's going to be stored and upload task.
And now within the callback once our state is set for upload task we can listen for state changed and
this will have a snap callback.
And in this callback will create this percent uploaded variable which will store the number of bytes
transferred in our upload with snapshot bytes transferred divided by the number of total bytes
and then to get the percent of the file has been uploaded will multiply bytes transferred divided by
total bytes by 100 or around that amount with Matha around to get an integer and then offset state so
we can track how much of the file has been uploaded over time
or create per cent uploaded within state and so that initially does 0.
Now after listening for state change we're going to include an error callback catching errors.
We just want to include a con. that air
said our errors array.
States have it include this potential error message with concat and if there's an error we'll set up
state to air and upload task to no.
Now after this state changed include another callback which will reference a snapshot property on upload
task than RF property and will execute this get download your L method which is going to be a promise
that's going to allow us to get the URL of the file that's been uploaded by firebase that we uploaded
to our base storage and we want to pass this download your L are all of that file to the send file message
function as well as ref and path to upload.
And once again since this is a promise we'll catch any errors
American paste and all the error handling that we used for our other error callback
now we need to create this send a message function will take the fire while your El read variable empath
to upload it on the.
We'll set a child path to upload or push that on to the.
And then also the result of the function create message which will take the file you are el.
So now we need to in order to post our message create the message with the value that's been returned
with create message will first delete the content property and and file your will as a parameter with
the default value of no.
So now will have messages both with content and with image properties.
So we need to determine which is which by setting a conditional where if there is a value or a pass
to create message we're going to set an image property on our message object called to file your bill
which we passed in.
Otherwise we'll have a content property which will be equal to the start state top message
in our back and send a message.
Could again
we want to once again set state or set up a state to dun
after we create and post our message and our captioning errors canceled or air
or add this air object to your heirs and state
funds for creating messages with images on them.
We need to display those images.
Within our message component we'll create an image function above message which will take a message
in return true if it contains an image property
right before the closing tag of comment that Conca will execute is image passen the message.
And if the function returns it to be an image message will show an image component with the source to
message that image was that the class name as well to message underscore underscore image otherwise.
If it's a message that contains a content property
we'll use our comment that text component and I'll just display the text with message content.
So then is image it's going to take the message it's going to check to see if it has a property with
the name of image and doesn't have a property with the name of content.
And now will create our message underscore underscore image class back within Appalachia SS and this
classes just to give the image that we're displaying a little bit of space around it on every side with
padding set to 1 am.
We'll save that and we'll make sure finally that we're bringing in the image component from semantic
UI.
We'll test this out by selecting an image file.
And when we hit send it should be uploaded to firebase storage.
We should see our new image message in the channel that we're currently in.
So if we head back to our database we should see a new message in our messages collection the property
of image.
So to the world firebase storage
we had to our storage tab.
You can see this new chat folder you can click on it then there will be a public folder and within that
we should see our uploaded image which was displayed as a message.
We can see the name size the file type as well as when it was created.