Within or upload for a function we have this state change.
Listener which listens for the percent of the file that was uploaded and said the state with that percentage
would be nice to represent this upload state.
Using a progress bar so create a progress for component to visually show or user.
How much of the file that they've chosen upload has been uploaded to import re-act up of the top.
This will be a stateless component.
Now at the bottom we'll export our progress for
and then within message form we want to put the progress bar underneath the buttons.
So first we'll move the file model underneath the button group and put the progress bar component underneath
that and up at the top.
We need to import progress for should be in the same folder the messages folder
and we want to pass it to values from state.
In particular the upload state the string that represents where the upload
the images and the percent uploaded are past both of those as props so grab both upload state and percent
uploaded from our state object.
Will this add this line above the destructuring to make sure my editor doesn't reformat that or pass
upload state to the upload state prop And percent uploaded to the pre-sent uploaded Propp then or then
progress bar we can do structure those props from our object props object
and or conditionally show this progress component based on whether there is some text for the upload.
If it's in the process of uploading then we'll show a progress component from semantic UI
as progress component will have a number of prox will first give it a class name of progress underscore
underscore bar the percent or the width of the progress bar will be determined by our percent uploaded.
Now you will be a progress or we'll have this indicating prompt to give it some additional styles that
have a size of medium.
Well give it the inverted Propp
within applets Yes as well.
Add a section for progress bar and include or one class of progress bar
will have a margin to zero point three M's zero zero zero on all other sides and set two important will
save the
better apple.
Try uploading a file to your first channel.
Pick an image file or hit send.
You can see our progress bar at the very bottom giving us our upload state and since we have our image
in our first channel we can see the images uploaded and therefore the progress bar has a percentage
of 100 percent.