There's one small thing to note whenever we add a new image file to a channel when we upload a file
by choosing it and hitting send I can see that our progress for as to the height of our message for
him and it gets in the way of our messages section in order to change that behavior.
The first approach would be to go to the progress bar and only show the progress bar whenever the upload
state or passing as a prop is set to the text uploading.
So as long as the images being uploaded will show the progress Barbeau once it's done it will go away.
That is the approach that I'll use.
And just to demonstrate this
choose another image
or hit send and the progress bar only sticks around as long as the image was uploading.
Now another post that you can take if you want the progress bar to stick around.
Or remove that conditional is to change the class of the messages complier the messages section so head
to our Aptos CSSA file.
We have our messages class here.
We add another class or if we have our progress bar we're going to use the class of messages underscore
or underscore progress and or change the height of our messages or original messages class to 62 new
height give it a responsive height and the message is progress.
Class will have a height of 58 height so a bit smaller.
So based on whether there's a progress bar you're going to use one class or another we'll do this with
a conditional check to see if there's a progress bar or use the class messages progress.
Otherwise we use the message as class
or create a function within our messages component called is progress for visible.
It's going to take the percent of the upload and it's going to check to see if percent greater than
zero.
And if so it's going to set the state of messages specifically the progress for property to True.
So create a progress for property.
She'll tell us if we have a progress bar or not will initially be set to false.
And then we can pass is progress bar visible down as a prompt to message form
and within message form within our state change listener will execute it.
If this process is progress for visible
we will pass in percent uploaded that function and it change the state of the parent component of the
messages component accordingly
within the Render of messages we need to structure the progress bar property so that our class name
ternary will work.
We save all of our files
and head back to our try uploading another media file or hit send.
We take a look at the messages section.
It was pulled up a bit since it has a smaller height and now there's a space between our messages component
and our messages form.